<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on iszlai - data,coffee and code</title>
    <link>http://iszlai.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on iszlai - data,coffee and code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 14:21:56 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://iszlai.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 week 47 in programming</title>
      <link>http://iszlai.github.io/post/2016_week_47_in_programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 14:21:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://iszlai.github.io/post/2016_week_47_in_programming/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;programmers-are-having-a-huge-discussion-about-the-unethical-and-illegal-things-they-ve-been-asked-to-do-http-www-businessinsider-com-programmers-confess-unethical-illegal-tasks-asked-of-them-2016-11&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/programmers-confess-unethical-illegal-tasks-asked-of-them-2016-11&#34;&gt; Programmers are having a huge discussion about the unethical and illegal things they’ve been asked to do &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dozens of people have already been killed by faulty software in cars, while hundreds of people have been killed from faulty software during air travel. &amp;ldquo;Uncle&amp;rdquo; Bob MartinYouTube/Expert Talks MobileBut Martin pointed out, &amp;ldquo;The weird thing is, it was software developers who wrote that code. It was us. Some programmers wrote cheating code. Do you think they knew? I think they probably knew.&amp;rdquo; Sourour&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Ashamed&amp;rdquo; post went viral on Hacker News and Reddit and it unleashed a long list of confessions from programmers about the unethical and, sometimes, illegal things they&amp;rsquo;ve been asked to do. Programmers then wrote scripts to help the company&amp;rsquo;s salespeople target these people. Now, he says, these same programmers are &amp;ldquo;Working on startups that scoop up massive amounts of people&amp;rsquo;s location data.&amp;rdquo; YouTube/&amp;ldquo;Uncle&amp;rdquo; Bob Martin - &amp;ldquo;The Future of Programming&amp;rdquo;Another programmer was hired to write software for a radio device and was asked to make it use channels reserved for emergency services because this would make the device operate faster. He warned, if programmers don&amp;rsquo;t start to govern themselves, after that apocalypse event that kills thousands of people occurs, legislators will do it for them, dictating everything about their jobs, down to the languages they are allowed to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;let-s-encrypt-everything-https-blog-codinghorror-com-lets-encrypt-everything&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.codinghorror.com/lets-encrypt-everything/&#34;&gt; Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt Everything &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The performance penalty of HTTPS is gone HTTPS arguably performs better than HTTP on modern devices. Historically these certificates have been issued by certificate authorities, and they were at least $30 per year per website, sometimes hundreds of dollars per year. Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt is a 501.3&amp;copy;(3) non-profit organization supported by the Linux Foundation. As a company, we&amp;rsquo;ve donated a Discourse hosted support community, and a cash amount that represents how much we would have paid in a year to one of the existing for-profit certificate authorities to set up HTTPS for all the Discourse websites we host. Estimate how much you would have paid for any free SSL certificates you obtained from Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt, and please donate that amount to Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt. If you work for a large company, urge them to sponsor Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt as a fundamental cornerstone of a safe web. If you believe in an unalienable right to privacy on the Internet for every citizen in every nation, please support Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;powershell-to-replace-cmd-as-windows-default-shell-inside-14971-https-blogs-windows-com-windowsexperience-2016-11-17-announcing-windows-10-insider-preview-build-14971-for-pc-veeb5jvwfl7qy4x4-97&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.windows.com/windowsexperience/2016/11/17/announcing-windows-10-insider-preview-build-14971-for-pc/#VeEB5jvwFL7Qy4x4.97&#34;&gt; Powershell to replace CMD as windows default shell (Inside 14971) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we are excited to be releasing Windows 10 Insider Preview Build 14971 for PC to Windows Insiders in the Fast ring. Read EPUB books in Microsoft Edge: The reading experience will get even better with the Windows 10 Creators Update! In addition to providing a great reading experience for PDF files - you can now read any unprotected e-book in the EPUB file format with Microsoft Edge. Bringing 3D to Everyone via the Paint 3D Preview app: Starting with this build and going forward, the Paint 3D Preview app is now included as part of Windows 10. Remix 3D Preview, the community counterpart to Paint 3D Preview, is expanding to Austria, Belgium, Denmark, Germany, Ireland, Netherlands, Norway, Sweden, and Switzerland for Windows Insiders today! Remix 3D Preview is currently only available in English but we will continue to expand our region and language support. For those who prefer to use Command Prompt, you can opt out of the WIN + X change by opening Settings &amp;gt; Personalization &amp;gt; Taskbar, and turning &amp;ldquo;Replace Command Prompt with Windows PowerShell in the menu when I right-click the Start button or press Windows key+X&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Off&amp;rdquo;. As we have previously announced we are working on the Windows Holographic Shell that is going to be included in the upcoming Windows 10 Creators Update. We love seeing our Windows Insiders organize #WINsiders4Good events on their own! This is exactly why we created the DIY kit and we love seeing you all use it to build relationships and solve problems in your communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-unfixable-bug-http-www-ilikebigbits-com-blog-2016-11-22-the-unfixable-bug&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ilikebigbits.com/blog/2016/11/22/the-unfixable-bug&#34;&gt; The Unfixable Bug &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before modeling a pretty car I started with something simpler: a box. I coded up a simple red box and dropped it into the terrain. At one point I changed the color of the box to white, relaunched the game and - there it was! A nice little box sitting in the landscape. Why would the box only be visible when it has a certain color? I checked the pixel shader. Everything seemed OK - but why was my box invisible when it was red? And only when it was red? I could find it when it was blue, white, black and purple. I tried resetting the color to red again and - WTH!? - there it was! I was back where I started code-wise, but now the box was visible again. As it turned out, the reason I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see the red box in the green landscape was simple: I am red-green color blind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-list-of-computer-science-courses-with-video-lectures-https-github-com-developer-y-cs-video-courses-blob-master-readme-md&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Developer-Y/cs-video-courses/blob/master/README.md&#34;&gt; A list of Computer Science courses with video lectures &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;information-wants-to-be-free-so-we-re-giving-away-our-400-intro-java-lectures-assignments-https-www-ktbyte-com-java-tutorial&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ktbyte.com/java-tutorial&#34;&gt; Information wants to be free, so we&amp;rsquo;re giving away our 400+ intro Java lectures / assignments &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;computer-science-legend-rear-adm-grace-hopper-posthumously-receives-presidential-medal-of-freedom-http-www-navy-mil-submit-display-asp-story-id-97807&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.navy.mil/submit/display.asp?story_id=97807&#34;&gt; Computer Science Legend, Rear Adm. Grace Hopper, Posthumously Receives Presidential Medal of Freedom &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grace Murray Hopper, best known for her advancements in computer programming and data processing, was awarded the Presidential Medal of Freedom posthumously by President Barack Obama during a White House ceremony Nov. 22. &amp;ldquo;While the women who pioneered software were often overlooked the most prestigious award for young computer scientists now bear her name,&amp;rdquo; he said, referring to the annual Grace Murray Hopper Award for Outstanding Young Computer Professionals, established in 1971 by the Association for Computing Machinery. To accept the award on Hopper&amp;rsquo;s behalf was her grand-niece Deborah Murray, who stood alongside the president as the citation was read, &amp;ldquo;As a child who loved disassembling alarm clocks Rear Adm. Grace Murray Hopper found her calling early. Known today as the&amp;rdquo;queen of code&amp;rdquo; Grace Hopper&amp;rsquo;s work helped make the coding language more practical and accessible&amp;hellip;Amazing Grace was committed to making the language of computer programming more universal. Today we honor her contributions to computer science and the sense of possibility she inspired for the generations of young people. There, she completed groundbreaking work in computer technology, including producing a model of the electronic computer, the Mark I, and introducing the word &amp;ldquo;Bug&amp;rdquo; to describe a computer malfunction. Often referred to as the &amp;ldquo;Mother of computing,&amp;rdquo; Hopper was instrumental in the creation of UNIVAC, the first all-electronic digital computer. Tighe, who has described Hopper as a role model, added, &amp;ldquo;Quite simply, and on many levels, Rear Adm. Grace Murray Hopper is an inspiration for us all. As a pioneer in computing, as a woman leading the way in the STEM field at a time when that was almost completely unheard of, and as a dedicated naval officer, she paved the way so that all of us who followed could succeed. All of us in the Information Warfare Community owe her our gratitude. The award of the Presidential Medal of Freedom is both well-earned and well deserved!&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;super-mario-bros-3-wrong-warp-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-fxzuzos7auk&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fxZuzos7Auk&#34;&gt; Super Mario Bros. 3 - Wrong Warp &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does the wrong warp actually work in Super Mario Bros. PATRONSThank you everyone for your help! It means so much to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;margaret-hamilton-apollo-software-engineer-awarded-presidential-medal-of-freedom-https-www-nasa-gov-feature-margaret-hamilton-apollo-software-engineer-awarded-presidential-medal-of-freedom&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nasa.gov/feature/margaret-hamilton-apollo-software-engineer-awarded-presidential-medal-of-freedom&#34;&gt; Margaret Hamilton, Apollo Software Engineer, Awarded Presidential Medal of Freedom &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-4-bit-calculator-made-in-cardboard-and-marble-http-lapinozz-github-io-learning-2016-11-19-calculator-with-caordboard-and-marbles-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lapinozz.github.io/learning/2016/11/19/calculator-with-caordboard-and-marbles.html&#34;&gt; A 4-bit Calculator made in cardboard and marble &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LOGIC. LOGIC is a fully functional 4-bit calculator made entirely out of cardboard, hot glue and marbles. You place your input numbers as binary in the inputs, a marble is a one, no marble is a zero. If there is no marble in: no marble outIf there is one marble in: no marble outIf there is two marble in: one marble out. If you have one marble than it passIf you have two marbles then they should cancel out. If there is one marble: make it fall in the first outputIf there is two marbles: make one of them fall in the second output. The first marble flip a little piece of cardboard, so if there is a second marble it fills fall in a hole. If there is one marble: make it fall in the first outputIf there is two marbles: make one of them fall in the second outputIf there is three marbles: make one the fall in the first output and another in the second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;humble-book-bundle-o-reilly-unix-books-https-www-humblebundle-com-books-unix-book-bundle&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.humblebundle.com/books/unix-book-bundle&#34;&gt; Humble Book Bundle: O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Unix books &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We called up our friends at O&amp;rsquo;Reilly to put together this bundle of Unix resources for all! Find your nutshell reference, your pocket guide, and your power tools here. O&amp;rsquo;Reilly has a bonus for us, too: Enter your email address to immediately receive an excerpt from &amp;ldquo;Ten Steps to Linux Survival&amp;rdquo; by Jim Lehmer. Learn Linux diagnostic and recovery tasks so you can jump in and fix a system problem when your site goes down! Together, these books would cost over $500. Here at Humble Bundle you name your price of $1 or more! These books are available in PDF, ePUB, and MOBI formats, meaning you can read them anywhere at any time. Instructions and a list of recommended reading programs can be found here. If you like what we do, you can leave us a Humble Tip too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rust-s-standard-hash-table-types-could-go-quadratic-x-post-r-rust-http-accidentallyquadratic-tumblr-com-post-153545455987-rust-hash-iteration-reinsertion&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://accidentallyquadratic.tumblr.com/post/153545455987/rust-hash-iteration-reinsertion&#34;&gt; “Rust’s standard hash table types could go quadratic.” [x-post /r/rust] &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand the bug, we&amp;rsquo;re going to need to understand the hash table strategy used by Rust&amp;rsquo;s standard hash tables. A major challenge in any general-purpose hash table implementation is how to handle hash collisions; If you have a table with N buckets, eventually you&amp;rsquo;ll get two elements with the same value of hashcode%N, and what do you do? In hash tables, &amp;ldquo;Open addressing&amp;rdquo; refers to the technique of, upon encountering a collision, somehow selecting an alternate location in the hash table. The problem occurs because iteration over a hash table procedes by walking the backing array of the hash table directly. They&amp;rsquo;re also speculating about a more fundamental fix to the hash table implementation, so that users who drop in a different hash algorithm are not again vulnerable. One proposal is that hash tables ought to retain their insertion order, since this bug is much less likely to happen if tables do not leak their hash order. Rust&amp;rsquo;s hash tables were very carefully thought by experienced developers well-versed in the literature and practice of deliberate quadratic attacks on hash tables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-balanced-ternary-machines-of-soviet-russia-https-dev-to-buntine-the-balanced-ternary-machines-of-soviet-russia&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/buntine/the-balanced-ternary-machines-of-soviet-russia&#34;&gt; The Balanced Ternary Machines of Soviet Russia &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Perhaps the prettiest number system of all is the balanced ternary notation&amp;rdquo; - Donald E. Knuth, The Art of Computer Programming, Vol. Enter Setun, a balanced ternary computer developed in 1958 by a small team led by Nikolay Brusentsov at the Moscow State University. In its balanced form, we can think of the ternary values as being &amp;ldquo;Balanced&amp;rdquo; around the mid-point of 0. In balanced ternary, as we&amp;rsquo;re about to discover, to represent the inverse of a number we simply have to swap all +&amp;rsquo;s with -&amp;rsquo;s and vice versa. The development of balanced ternary machines has all but faded into a small footnote in the annals of computer history. For the moment at least, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that you&amp;rsquo;ll be hearing much more about balanced ternary computers in the near future. Although Setun was the first electronic device to operate on balanced ternary, it&amp;rsquo;s worth mentioning that the idea of using balanced ternary in computing devices was first popularized over 100 years before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-rebuttal-for-python-3-https-eev-ee-blog-2016-11-23-a-rebuttal-for-python-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://eev.ee/blog/2016/11/23/a-rebuttal-for-python-3/&#34;&gt; A Rebuttal For Python 3 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You only &amp;ldquo;Cannot&amp;rdquo; run Python 2 inside the Python 3 VM because no one has written a Python 2 interpreter in Python 3. Python 3 comes with a tool called 2to3 which is supposed to take Python 2 code and translate it to Python 3 code. So my Python 3 code, written and intended purely for Python 3, now has to deal with Python 2 integers as well. What about the standard library, which has had a number of improvements in Python 3 that don&amp;rsquo;t or can&amp;rsquo;t exist in Python 2? Should Python ship two entire separate copies of its standard library? What about modules like logging, which rely on global state? Does Python 2 and Python 3 code need to set up logging separately within the same process? Python 3 has been purposefully crippled to prevent Python 2&amp;rsquo;s execution alongside Python 3 for someone&amp;rsquo;s professional or ideological gain. By the way, did you know that several error messages are much improved in Python 3? Python 2 is somewhat notorious for the confusing errors it produces when an argument is missing from a method call, but Python 3 is specific about the problem, which is much friendlier to beginners. Now we&amp;rsquo;re finally, finally at the point where virtually all libraries support Python 3, a few new ones only support Python 3, and Python 3 adoption is starting to take hold among application developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-in-c-code-http-stackoverflow-com-questions-9229601-what-is-in-c-code&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/9229601/what-is-in-c-code&#34;&gt; What is &amp;ldquo;:-!!&amp;rdquo; in C code? &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another common mechanism is to call a function that isn&amp;rsquo;t defined and rely on the optimizer to compile-out the function call if your assertion is correct. In sympathy for the need for compile-time assertions, GCC 4.3 introduced the the error function attribute that allows you to extend upon this older concept, but generate a compile-time error with a message of your choosing - no more cryptic &amp;ldquo;Negative sized array&amp;rdquo; error messages! This macro will evaluate its parameter exactly once and create a compile-time error that says &amp;ldquo;I told you not to give me a five!&amp;rdquo; if the expression evaluates to five or is not a compile-time constant. So why aren&amp;rsquo;t we using this instead of negative-sized bit-fields? Alas, there are currently many restrictions of the use of statement expressions, including their use as constant initializers even if the statement expression is completely constant its self test). Hopefully, GCC will amend these shortcomings soon and allow constant statement expressions to be used as constant initializers. The challenge here is the language specification defining what is a legal constant expression. So I hope that gcc can make a constexpr functionality available as an extension via -std=gnuc99 &amp;amp; -std=gnuc11 or some such and allow its use on statement expressions et.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rider-a-crossplatform-c-ide-by-jetbrains-now-in-public-eap-https-blog-jetbrains-com-dotnet-2016-11-21-jetbrains-rider-public-preview&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/dotnet/2016/11/21/jetbrains-rider-public-preview/&#34;&gt; Rider, a crossplatform C# IDE by Jetbrains now in public EAP &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we&amp;rsquo;re not quite feature complete, and there are still a couple of rough edges, we know of many people, inside and outside of JetBrains, who are already using Rider for day-to-day development. TL;DR:. Download the first public Rider EAP build. While the plugin SDK is still under development, Rider already supports both IntelliJ and ReSharper plugins, so Rider can take advantage of existing IntelliJ plugins such as VIM editing mode. Check out Hadi&amp;rsquo;s Rider Tips and Tricks video from NDC Sydney for more examples of how the IntelliJ platform will help you using Rider. Remember, Rider is built from the ReSharper codebase - Rider IS ReSharper. So that&amp;rsquo;s what it&amp;rsquo;s going to be - welcome to JetBrains Rider. Download the first public Rider EAP build from the web site, or fire up Toolbox: Rider&amp;rsquo;s going to be there as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-not-change-linux-files-using-windows-apps-and-tools-https-blogs-msdn-microsoft-com-commandline-2016-11-17-do-not-change-linux-files-using-windows-apps-and-tools&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/commandline/2016/11/17/do-not-change-linux-files-using-windows-apps-and-tools/&#34;&gt; Do not change Linux files using Windows apps and tools &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DO NOT, under ANY circumstances, create and/or modify Linux files using Windows apps, tools, scripts, consoles, etc. Creating/changing Linux files from Windows will likely result in data corruption and/or damage your Linux environment requiring you to uninstall &amp;amp; reinstall your distro! If WSL can&amp;rsquo;t find Linux file metadata for a given file, it assumes the file is corrupted/damaged, and will likely fail to open/read the file correctly, causing apps, tools, etc. Several Windows tools implement different strategies to handle file updating and don&amp;rsquo;t actually edit files in-place. To work on files using both Windows and Linux tools, store &amp;amp; work on those files in your Windows filesystem, and access them from both Windows and from Bash via /mnt/&lt;drive&gt;/path. So you can easily access the same files using both Windows tools and Bash tools without having to copy files back and forth between filesystems. DO store files in your Windows filesystem that you want to create/modify using Windows tools AND Linux tools DO NOT create / modify Linux files from Windows apps, tools, scripts or consoles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;steven-skiena-s-lectures-on-algorithms-and-data-structures-last-updated-2012-http-www3-cs-stonybrook-edu-algorith-video-lectures&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www3.cs.stonybrook.edu/~algorith/video-lectures/&#34;&gt; Steven Skiena&amp;rsquo;s lectures on Algorithms and Data Structures (last updated 2012) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are audio, video and lecture sides for 1997 and 2007. Since the lectures are 10 years apart some of the topics covered by the course have changed. The 1997 lectures have a better quality video and audio than the 2007, although the 2007 covers the newer material and has better lecture notes. If you found this useful also check out the video lectures of my Discrete Mathematics, Computational Biology, and Computational Finance courses. To download audio, right click and choose `Save Page As&amp;rsquo;. Topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;opengl-renderer-design-how-i-write-opengl-these-days-https-nlguillemot-wordpress-com-2016-11-18-opengl-renderer-design&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nlguillemot.wordpress.com/2016/11/18/opengl-renderer-design/&#34;&gt; OpenGL Renderer Design (how I write OpenGL these days) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a typical renderer, you might have a table of all the materials, a table of all the meshes, a table of all the instances of meshes, a table of all the cameras, and etc. The specifics of these tables depends on your project, so if you&amp;rsquo;re doing a skeletal animation project you would also have a table of the skeletons, instances of skeletons, and so on. Table usually have a &amp;ldquo;Primary key&amp;rdquo;, which can be used to identify each object in the table uniquely, and can also be used to efficiently lookup the object. Each mesh instance would then have a foreign key to the mesh table, and a foreign key to the transform table. I should point out that since my Scene class is implemented only in terms of plain OpenGL objects, that makes it easy for anybody to write an OpenGL renderer that reads the contents of the tables and renders them in whatever way they see fit. You might have a table for all the transforms, a table for mesh instances, and a table for meshes. To support relative transformations, I suggest creating a new table that stores the edges of the transformation tree, meaning each object in the table stores the foreign keys of two transforms: The parent and the child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;git-also-for-a-file-in-your-git-repository-prints-other-files-that-are-most-often-committed-together-https-github-com-anvaka-git-also-git-also&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/anvaka/git-also#git-also&#34;&gt; &lt;code&gt;git also&lt;/code&gt; - for a file in your git repository prints other files that are most often committed together &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a file in your git repository, prints other files that are most often committed together. &amp;gt; src/core/Object3D.js most often committed with: # together Similarity Name 51 0.22 src/core/Geometry. This means that file Object3D.js is most often committed with Geometry. The Similarity column shows Jaccard index of two files. Usage: git-also [options] &lt;file&gt; For a &lt;file&gt; in your git repository prints other files that are most often committed together Options: -h, -help output usage information -V, -version output the version number -c, -count &lt;n&gt; Print top N other files. Files are often committed together when developers improve code or add new features. What are related file to this file? Where else should I look when I fix bugs in this file?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;composition-over-inheritance-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-wfmtdgfhwpa-t-2s&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wfMtDGfHWpA&amp;amp;t=2s&#34;&gt; Composition over Inheritance &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a weekly show where we try to become more confident and excited about programming by learning intriguing things that we didn&amp;rsquo;t know before. Today, we are are going to talk about composition over inheritance. Inheritance is when you design your types after what they are, while composition is when you design your types after what they cando. We are going to learn about the limitations of inheritance, and how to solve them using composition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-source-net-2-years-later-http-www-mattwarren-org-2016-11-23-open-source-net-2-years-later&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mattwarren.org/2016/11/23/open-source-net-2-years-later/&#34;&gt; Open Source .NET – 2 years later &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little over 2 years ago Microsoft announced that they were open sourcing large parts of the. First we are going to see an overview of the level of activity in each repo, by looking at the total number of &amp;lsquo;Issues&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Pull Requests&amp;rsquo; per month. The main trend I see across all repos is there&amp;rsquo;s a sustained level of activity for the entire 2 years, things didn&amp;rsquo;t start with a bang and then tailed off. This data represents the total participation from the last 2 years, i.e. November 2014 to October 2016. Finally we can see the &amp;lsquo;per-month&amp;rsquo; data from the last 2 years, i.e. November 2014 to October 2016. Whilst not every repo is growing month-by-month, the majority are and those that aren&amp;rsquo;t at least show sustained contributions across 2 years. I think that it&amp;rsquo;s clear to see that the Community has got on-board with the new Open-Source Microsoft, producing a sustained level of contributions over the last 2 years, lets hope it continues!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;great-tutorial-on-learning-to-think-abstractly-and-analyze-algorithms-old-article-one-of-the-best-http-worrydream-com-ladderofabstraction&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://worrydream.com/LadderOfAbstraction/&#34;&gt; Great tutorial on learning to think abstractly and analyze algorithms (old article, one of the best) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When creating abstractions, stepping down is as important as stepping up. Here, we take the abstraction from the previous section, and overlay a concrete representation on top of it. Every point on a visual abstraction typically corresponds to a particular concrete state. Pointing at the abstraction to step down to a concrete representation lets us quickly explore regions of interest. In the concrete representation it jumps out at us, because it violates our common sense. That is, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to step down from the abstraction just in our heads. We&amp;rsquo;re not far off the ground yet! As we climb higher on the ladder of abstraction, it will become harder to imagine the concrete steps beneath, and more critical that our abstractions provide a way to interactively step down to a more concrete representation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sophie-wilson-the-future-of-microprocessors-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-9mzmvhwmqw&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_9mzmvhwMqw&#34;&gt; Sophie Wilson - The Future of Microprocessors &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;her-code-got-humans-on-the-moon-and-invented-software-itself-https-www-wired-com-2015-10-margaret-hamilton-nasa-apollo&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/2015/10/margaret-hamilton-nasa-apollo/&#34;&gt; Her Code Got Humans on the Moon—And Invented Software Itself &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Margaret Hamilton wasn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to invent the modern concept of software and land men on the moon. Hamilton, a 24-year-old with an undergrad degree in mathematics, had gotten a job as a programmer at MIT, and the plan was for her to support her husband through his three-year stint at Harvard Law. As a working mother in the 1960s, Hamilton was unusual; but as a spaceship programmer, Hamilton was positively radical. Hamilton would bring her daughter Lauren by the lab on weekends and evenings. Like female coders in today&amp;rsquo;s diversity-challenged tech industry, Hamilton was an outlier. As Hamilton&amp;rsquo;s career got under way, the software world was on the verge of a giant leap, thanks to the Apollo program launched by John F. Kennedy in 1961. At the MIT Instrumentation Lab where Hamilton worked, she and her colleagues were inventing core ideas in computer programming as they wrote the code for the world&amp;rsquo;s first portable computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 week 46 in programming</title>
      <link>http://iszlai.github.io/post/2016_week_46_in_programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 14:21:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://iszlai.github.io/post/2016_week_46_in_programming/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;programmers-are-having-a-huge-discussion-about-the-unethical-and-illegal-things-they-ve-been-asked-to-do-http-www-businessinsider-com-programmers-confess-unethical-illegal-tasks-asked-of-them-2016-11&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/programmers-confess-unethical-illegal-tasks-asked-of-them-2016-11&#34;&gt; Programmers are having a huge discussion about the unethical and illegal things they’ve been asked to do &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dozens of people have already been killed by faulty software in cars, while hundreds of people have been killed from faulty software during air travel. Martin pointed out, &amp;ldquo;The weird thing is, it was software developers who wrote that code. It was us. Some programmers wrote cheating code. Do you think they knew? I think they probably knew.&amp;rdquo; Sourour&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Ashamed&amp;rdquo; post went viral on Hacker News and Reddit and it unleashed a long list of confessions from programmers about the unethical and, sometimes, illegal things they&amp;rsquo;ve been asked to do. Programmers then wrote scripts to help the company&amp;rsquo;s salespeople target these people. Now, he says, these same programmers are &amp;ldquo;Working on startups that scoop up massive amounts of people&amp;rsquo;s location data.&amp;rdquo; Another programmer was hired to write software for a radio device and was asked to make it use channels reserved for emergency services because this would make the device operate faster. He warned, if programmers don&amp;rsquo;t start to govern themselves, after that apocalypse event that kills thousands of people occurs, legislators will do it for them, dictating everything about their jobs, down to the languages they are allowed to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-code-i-m-still-ashamed-of-https-medium-freecodecamp-com-the-code-im-still-ashamed-of-e4c021dff55e-vmbgbtgin&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/the-code-im-still-ashamed-of-e4c021dff55e#.vmbgbtgin&#34;&gt; The code I’m still ashamed of &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you write code for a living, there&amp;rsquo;s a chance that at some point in your career, someone will ask you to code something a little deceitful - if not outright unethical. In Canada, there are strict limits on how pharmaceutical companies can advertise prescription drugs directly to consumers. As a result, these companies would create websites that present general information about whatever symptoms their drugs were meant to address. In the end, I understood that the real purpose of the site was to push a particular drug. We had discovered while working on the project that she had actually been prescribed the very drug I was building a site for. Still, I&amp;rsquo;ve never felt okay about writing that code. It&amp;rsquo;s not hard to imagine them recommending prescription drugs soon, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;microsoft-joins-the-linux-foundation-as-a-platinum-member-http-venturebeat-com-2016-11-16-microsoft-joins-the-linux-foundation-as-a-platinum-member&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://venturebeat.com/2016/11/16/microsoft-joins-the-linux-foundation-as-a-platinum-member/&#34;&gt; Microsoft joins The Linux Foundation as a Platinum member &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its Connect(); 2016 developer event in New York City today, Microsoft announced it is joining The Linux Foundation. Microsoft already contributes to several of its projects, including Node.js Foundation, OpenDaylight, Open Container Initiative, R Consortium, and Open API Initiative. &amp;ldquo;Microsoft has grown and matured in its use of and contributions to open-source technology,&amp;rdquo; The Linux Foundation executive director Jim Zemlin said in a statement. &amp;ldquo;The company has become an enthusiastic supporter of Linux and of open-source and a very active member of many important projects. Membership is an important step for Microsoft, but also for the open-source community at large, which stands to benefit from the company&amp;rsquo;s expanding range of contributions.&amp;rdquo; We interviewed Zemlin, who was excited to elaborate on the news, noting that The Linux Foundation and Microsoft started conversations about membership earlier this year. Microsoft naturally stands to benefit as well, and not just in terms of PR. In addition to Microsoft taking an active role in making the organization better, membership means the company can better collaborate with the open-source community to improve mobile and cloud technology that millions rely on. &amp;ldquo;The Linux Foundation is home not only to Linux, but many of the community&amp;rsquo;s most innovative open-source projects. We are excited to join The Linux Foundation and partner with the community to help developers capitalize on the shift to intelligent cloud and mobile experiences.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-learn-programming-do-projects-you-actually-care-about-https-datarebellion-com-blog-to-learn-programming-do-projects-you-actually-care-about&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://datarebellion.com/blog/to-learn-programming-do-projects-you-actually-care-about/&#34;&gt; To Learn Programming, Do Projects You Actually Care About &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Rebellion is all about getting your programming abilities to the point of usefulness as quickly as possible. Now, a majority of the time the fate of the planet won&amp;rsquo;t depend on your latest Python project. Have you ever had the experience where you start a course and get through the first few lectures, only to forget about it the next week? Or download an ebook and never get around to opening it? Or get bored of artificial exercises? Or lose interest in a project you know isn&amp;rsquo;t really useful to you or that you don&amp;rsquo;t truly care about? Personally, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost count of all the things I&amp;rsquo;ve started and never finished. Sounds kind of pathetic, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it? But at that point I was starting to get a feel for the language, and I came up with a personal project I was genuinely interested in: writing a program that composed music. It didn&amp;rsquo;t win any Grammy&amp;rsquo;s, but going through the entire process of envisioning an ambitious project, methodically working through it, and ending with an actual working product brought me to a whole new level in programming, more so than any course or ebook ever did. So if you&amp;rsquo;re in the beginning-to-intermediate stages of your programming journey, here&amp;rsquo;s my suggestion to you: find a need or passion of yours that you think might just be possible to address with code and start working on it ASAP. Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of projects to jump-start your thinking. If you can&amp;rsquo;t see exactly how to get from point A to point B, good! That means you&amp;rsquo;re going to learn something along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;8-million-github-profiles-were-leaked-from-geekedin-s-mongodb-https-www-troyhunt-com-8-million-github-profiles-were-leaked-from-geekedins-mongodb-heres-how-to-see-yours&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.troyhunt.com/8-million-github-profiles-were-leaked-from-geekedins-mongodb-heres-how-to-see-yours/&#34;&gt; 8 million GitHub profiles were leaked from GeekedIn&amp;rsquo;s MongoDB &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of any implementation within GitHub that publicly exposed this information for the purpose of mass consumption, and frankly, by now it was starting to smell a bit bad&amp;hellip;. Last thing before I start talking about disclosure: when I analysed the data set I found almost 8.2 million unique email addresses. Moving on, given what I&amp;rsquo;d seen thus far I decided to reach out to GitHub directly as it was their data that was involved here, even if it was leaked from another service. Particularly if data was circulating among traders, there was every chance people would start popping up and saying &amp;ldquo;Hey, I&amp;rsquo;ve got the GitHub data breach&amp;rdquo;. Third parties frequently scrape public GitHub data for various reasons, such as research or archival purposes. It is wrong, not just the scraping of GitHub in the first place in order to commercialise our information, but then subsequently losing it via a MongoDB with no password and now having it float around the web in data breach trading circles. No, it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been aggregated en masse and no, it definitely shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been leaked, but it is data that on a per-individual basis you can go and retrieve from anyone&amp;rsquo;s GitHub profile. That&amp;rsquo;s it! Once again, you&amp;rsquo;re only going to show up here if your email address was successfully pulled from GitHub, but I hope it&amp;rsquo;s useful for the million plus people whose data was exposed somewhere they never expected it to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-machine-learning-for-developers-http-blog-algorithmia-com-introduction-machine-learning-developers&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.algorithmia.com/introduction-machine-learning-developers/&#34;&gt; Introduction to Machine Learning for developers &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s developers often hear about leveraging machine learning algorithms in order to build more intelligent applications, but many don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start. One of the most important aspects of developing smart applications is to understand the underlying machine learning models, even if you aren&amp;rsquo;t the person building them. Machine learning studies computer algorithms for learning to do stuff. Machine learning is about learning to do better in the future based on what was experienced in the past. The two main types of machine learning algorithms are supervised and unsupervised learning. Pandas is a Python library that uses data frames such as R. While it slow to use in production, Pandas is a favorite in using for data analysis and machine learning in a Python environment. Scikit-learn is another favorite Python library and is a great place to find machine learning models with tutorials and documentation that have been vetted by many Python developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;google-joins-net-foundation-https-techcrunch-com-2016-11-16-google-signs-on-to-the-net-foundation-and-samsung-brings-net-support-to-tizen&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2016/11/16/google-signs-on-to-the-net-foundation-and-samsung-brings-net-support-to-tizen/&#34;&gt; Google joins .NET Foundation &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NET Foundation, the open-source organization Microsoft established to guide the future development of the. NET Foundation, where it joins the likes of Red Hat, Unity, Samsung JetBrains and Microsoft in the Technical Steering Group. NET applications thanks to its support for Windows Server, and offers. NET by launching support for it on its Tizen platform. As Samsung&amp;rsquo;s Hong-Seok Kim told me, Samsung was looking for a framework in addition to the web framework and C API that Tizen developers currently use to write their applications. &amp;ldquo;We looked into alternatives but.NET was superior,&amp;rdquo; he said and noted that Samsung was looking for a framework with a strong foundation in terms of language support, APIs and tooling, as well as one with a large built-in developer base and open-source community. NET&amp;rsquo;s existing ecosystem, Samsung surely hopes that this move will also broaden its own Tizen developer ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-we-make-money-at-stack-overflow-2016-edition-http-stackoverflow-blog-2016-11-how-we-make-money-at-stack-overflow-2016-edition&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.blog/2016/11/How-We-Make-Money-at-Stack-Overflow-2016-Edition/&#34;&gt; How We Make Money at Stack Overflow: 2016 Edition &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more companies and developers we have, the better and faster the matching we can do with developers and hopefully their dream jobs. I helped build this because I think it&amp;rsquo;s an awesome way we can improve life over resumes and CVs. It helps developers show off who they are, the things they do, and in an approachable way that&amp;rsquo;s maintainable. While we&amp;rsquo;d love to help match you to a perfect company, we built both Jobs and Developer Story to support our core mission of serving ALL developers, including those of you who just don&amp;rsquo;t care about job searching right now. We&amp;rsquo;re working to change how companies treat developers not only through the standards built into Jobs, but also through our Developer Hiring Blog, which we created for the express purpose of improving employer and recruiter practices. With Developer Story, we want to change the perception that developers are only as good as their last gig or a title. We&amp;rsquo;re going to spend more time developing Stack Overflow Enterprise. We are in the process of sending out an email now announcing Developer Story to the larger community in the hopes that we can help some percentage of developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;glacially-slow-ip-over-qr-code-tunnel-http-seiferteric-com-p-356&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://seiferteric.com/?p=356&#34;&gt; Glacially Slow IP Over QR Code Tunnel! &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time I wanted to send data using your monitor and a webcam, but how could I send data reliably without too much work? QR Code! So the idea this time is to use a tun device, read packets from it, convert to QR Code and display on screen. First, you need some way to acknowledge that the other side read my message, so I added a simple header of the form SEQ/ACK where I increment the sequence with each new qrcode and increment the acknowledge when I successfully read the other sides qr code. QR Codes support a binary mode, but this is the least efficient and decided to instead use alphanumeric and base32 encode the packet data. Base64 would not work because the QR Code in this mode only supports uppercase letters. Next was an issue were the library I used to encode the data, qrtools, would generate a qr code, but the data would not be the same when decoding! So I fixed this by detecting this, then adding some padding to the data and trying again until it works, then strip the padding off on the other side. To maintain my sanity during testing, I was able to run the code in a docker container for the remote side, and instead of using webcam, just pass the qr code image file in a volume mount. Speeeeeeed! Only rewrite qrcode when new data is available pack as much data into a qrcode as possible cleanup code, fix syn/ack to avoid packet dups better detection library? Get a better camera for the laptop? Non-vertical youtube videos 🙂. Related.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-calculate-a-nation-state-s-election-result-in-your-bedroom-https-medium-com-michaelsproul-how-to-calculate-a-nation-states-election-result-in-your-bedroom-30f0c5d905af&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@michaelsproul/how-to-calculate-a-nation-states-election-result-in-your-bedroom-30f0c5d905af&#34;&gt; How to calculate a nation state’s election result in your bedroom &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, on July 11 - a week after the election itself - I started hacking away on some code to compute the election result from the CSV files published on the AEC&amp;rsquo;s website. STV what now?The Australian senate uses a proportional representation system called single transferable vote which allows voters to specify several candidates they&amp;rsquo;d like to vote for in order of least to most evil. If your first choice doesn&amp;rsquo;t get enough votes to be elected, your vote is transferred to your second, and so on, until either you run out of people you can bring yourself to vote for, or all the available spots in the senate are filled. The ballot parsing is the most nuanced, as we have to enforce rules about the number of candidates each voter has to specify, and decide which vote to count if someone has voted both above the line and below the line. Although it&amp;rsquo;s tempting to represent these fractions as floating point numbers, this will result in an inevitable loss of accuracy, which could throw the whole election result off. Interestingly, the result of the 2016 election seems reasonably stable with respect to minor alterations of the algorithm and ballot validation rules. Are voting errors uniformly distributed across political allegiances? If not, could the AEC tweak the validation rules to alter the result? Does rounding favour small or large parties? Would we better off paying the computational price to use an exact algorithm with no rounding at all?Pretty graphs related to either of the above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;elasticsearch-adventures-in-scaling-a-multitenant-platform-http-www-bigeng-io-elasticsearch-scaling-multitenant&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bigeng.io/elasticsearch-scaling-multitenant/&#34;&gt; Elasticsearch: Adventures in scaling a multitenant platform &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our previous production platform assigned each store to a single shard, in a single index. With limited information available at the time of implementation and without a reasonably defined set of product requirements, the hypothesis was that it would be faster for Elasticsearch to only have to query a single shard rather than broadcasting the query over the entire cluster of up to 60+ shards. Stores with big catalogs could create shards upto 150GB Unbalanced shards, data is not distributed evenly over all shards Massive shards take a significant amount of time to relocate when the index is re-sharded Massive shards cause heap stress resulting in heavy Garbage Collection and stop the world events Routed index causes nodes with big shards to get &amp;ldquo;Hot&amp;rdquo; Often seen during traffic bursts and site crawling Causes poor responses times for other stores on shards on those nodes Causes GC pauses on nodes. Must be scalable to allow faceted search for all stores Should limit shard sizes to &amp;lt;50GB Should limit JVM heap size to around 16GB Must be able to meet and exceed current and historical load from current platform Should stick to Elasticsearch default configurations as much as possible, the fewer tweaks the better. Using shard allocation filtering, we can create multiple indexes and assign their shards to particular nodes, essentially creating small clusters within the overall larger cluster. Having fewer shards increases the performance, seemingly regardless of the number of shards. So now to find the documents for any given store, we only need to query 8 shards so we only have to wait for those 8 shards to be searched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mssql-sever-for-linux-runs-on-user-mode-nt-kernel-library-http-www-theregister-co-uk-2016-11-18-microsoft-running-windows-apps-on-linux&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2016/11/18/microsoft_running_windows_apps_on_linux/&#34;&gt; MSSQL Sever for Linux runs on user-mode NT kernel library &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March, when Microsoft announced plans to release SQL Server for Linux, Scott Guthrie, EVP of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s cloud and enterprise group, said, &amp;ldquo;This will enable SQL Server to deliver a consistent data platform across Windows Server and Linux, as well as on-premises and cloud.&amp;rdquo; The release of the first public preview of SQL Server for Linux on Wednesday reveals just how consistent that platform is: It&amp;rsquo;s the Windows version of SQL Server running on the Windows NT kernel as a guest app, more or less. Microsoft could have ported SQL Server to run as a native Linux application. SQL Server for Linux runs atop a Drawbridge Windows library OS - a user-mode NT kernel - within a secure container called a picoprocess that communicates with the host Linux operating system through the Drawbridge application binary interface. In other words, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s SQL Server for Linux is really the Windows SQL Server executable with a small Windows 8 kernel glued underneath, all running in a normal Linux process. In theory, Microsoft can use this technology to bring its other Windows server applications to Linux with minimal changes, using SQL Server as a starting point. Where once Linux was a cancer to Microsoft, now Windows is growing inside of Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-easily-modify-regular-expressions-someone-else-wrote-https-medium-com-yumenohosi-visualizing-regular-expressions-regexper-com-dade9ae3f0ab&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@yumenohosi/visualizing-regular-expressions-regexper-com-dade9ae3f0ab&#34;&gt; How to easily modify regular expressions someone else wrote &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When confronted with a problem, think &amp;ldquo;I know, I&amp;rsquo;ll use regular expressions.&amp;rdquo; Now they have two problems. I&amp;rsquo;m not completely sure where I stand as to the universal utility of regular expressions, but I did meet with a problem recently with the markdown parser that our team was using on a project. As I needed an immediate fix, I went to the source, soon finding myself amidst regular expressions like the following. Then I remembered having seen a service called regexper.com, a site that helps turn regular expression strings into something like this. Anyway, this was how the regular expression turned out for me. Regular expressions that were once hard to describe using only words, with the help of imaging, are now much easier to express and understand. Satisfied with the results, and since I was on the subject, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d apply &amp;ldquo;Regexper&amp;rdquo; on all the regular expressions that showed up in the &amp;ldquo;Marked&amp;rdquo; module I was working with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-write-an-object-oriented-program-that-doesn-t-suck-https-dev-to-naveen-how-to-write-an-object-oriented-program-that-doesnt-suck&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/naveen/how-to-write-an-object-oriented-program-that-doesnt-suck&#34;&gt; How to write an object oriented program that doesn&amp;rsquo;t suck &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have seen many computer programmers proudly proclaim &amp;ldquo;Yup, I designed my code in an object oriented way - I have defined my data members as private, they can be only accessed through public methods - I have created base classes and sub-classes that follow a hierarchy - I have created virtual methods in the base class that shares common behavior that can be used in derived classes.&amp;rdquo; Is that what object orientation is all about? There is definitely more to it. Now the Account class has the flexibility to delegate the logging activity to the Logger class and it can focus only on Account related activities. Can we try extending the code by adding a new class whenever a new account type needs to be added and inherit it from Account class? By doing so, we are not only abstracting the Account class but also allowing it to share common behavior across it&amp;rsquo;s child classes. The OnlineAccount class will only implement IProcessInterest while the Account class will implement both IProcessInterest and IWithdrawable. Let&amp;rsquo;s go back to the first issue we resolved where we added Logger class to delegate the responsibility of logging from Account class. We are again violating the Account class by giving more responsibility to decide which instance of the Logging class to be created. It is not the job of Account class to decide on object creation for logging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-google-ai-experiment-quick-draw-have-google-s-neural-network-guess-your-doodles-https-aiexperiments-withgoogle-com-quick-draw&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aiexperiments.withgoogle.com/quick-draw&#34;&gt; New Google AI Experiment - Quick Draw - Have Google&amp;rsquo;s Neural Network guess your doodles &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You draw, and a neural network tries to guess what you&amp;rsquo;re drawing. The more you play with it, the more it will learn. It&amp;rsquo;s just one example of how you can use machine learning in fun ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;powershell-to-replace-cmd-as-windows-default-shell-inside-14971-https-blogs-windows-com-windowsexperience-2016-11-17-announcing-windows-10-insider-preview-build-14971-for-pc-veeb5jvwfl7qy4x4-97&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.windows.com/windowsexperience/2016/11/17/announcing-windows-10-insider-preview-build-14971-for-pc/#VeEB5jvwFL7Qy4x4.97&#34;&gt; Powershell to replace CMD as windows default shell (Inside 14971) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we are excited to be releasing Windows 10 Insider Preview Build 14971 for PC to Windows Insiders in the Fast ring. Read EPUB books in Microsoft Edge: The reading experience will get even better with the Windows 10 Creators Update! In addition to providing a great reading experience for PDF files - you can now read any unprotected e-book in the EPUB file format with Microsoft Edge. Bringing 3D to Everyone via the Paint 3D Preview app: Starting with this build and going forward, the Paint 3D Preview app is now included as part of Windows 10. Remix 3D Preview, the community counterpart to Paint 3D Preview, is expanding to Austria, Belgium, Denmark, Germany, Ireland, Netherlands, Norway, Sweden, and Switzerland for Windows Insiders today! Remix 3D Preview is currently only available in English but we will continue to expand our region and language support. For those who prefer to use Command Prompt, you can opt out of the WIN + X change by opening Settings &amp;gt; Personalization &amp;gt; Taskbar, and turning &amp;ldquo;Replace Command Prompt with Windows PowerShell in the menu when I right-click the Start button or press Windows key+X&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Off&amp;rdquo;. As we have previously announced we are working on the Windows Holographic Shell that is going to be included in the upcoming Windows 10 Creators Update. We love seeing our Windows Insiders organize #WINsiders4Good events on their own! This is exactly why we created the DIY kit and we love seeing you all use it to build relationships and solve problems in your communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;grace-hopper-posthumously-awarded-presidential-medal-of-freedom-https-www-whitehouse-gov-the-press-office-2016-11-16-president-obama-names-recipients-presidential-medal-freedom&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2016/11/16/president-obama-names-recipients-presidential-medal-freedom&#34;&gt; Grace Hopper posthumously awarded Presidential Medal of Freedom &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Presidential Medal of Freedom is the Nation&amp;rsquo;s highest civilian honor, presented to individuals who have made especially meritorious contributions to the security or national interests of the United States, to world peace, or to cultural or other significant public or private endeavors. The awards will be presented at the White House on November 22nd. President Obama said, &amp;ldquo;The Presidential Medal of Freedom is not just our nation&amp;rsquo;s highest civilian honor - it&amp;rsquo;s a tribute to the idea that all of us, no matter where we come from, have the opportunity to change this country for the better. From scientists, philanthropists, and public servants to activists, athletes, and artists, these 21 individuals have helped push America forward, inspiring millions of people around the world along the way.&amp;rdquo; He has been nominated for the Academy Award for Best Actor in a Leading Role five times, and received the award for his work in Philadelphia and Forrest Gump. During his career, he won six championships, five Most Valuable Player awards, and appeared in 14 All-Star games. Diana Ross is an Academy Award nominee, inductee into the Rock &amp;amp; Roll Hall of Fame, and recipient of the Grammy Awards highest honor, the Lifetime Achievement Award. She has won two Emmy Awards and a Tony Award, and is known for her performances in Sounder, The Autobiography of Miss Jane Pittman, and The Help. In 2013, she returned to the stage with The Trip to the Bountiful, and was awarded the Tony Award for best leading actress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;amazon-to-drop-dreaded-stack-ranking-performance-reviews-http-www-seattletimes-com-business-amazon-amazon-says-it-will-change-performance-reviews-focus-on-staffers-strengths&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.seattletimes.com/business/amazon/amazon-says-it-will-change-performance-reviews-focus-on-staffers-strengths/&#34;&gt; Amazon to drop dreaded stack-ranking performance reviews &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re launching a new annual review process next year that is radically simplified and focuses on our employees&amp;rsquo; strengths, not the absence of weaknesses,&amp;rdquo; Amazon spokeswoman Teal Pennebaker said. The changes, first reported by tech news site GeekWire and set to become effective in 2017, make Amazon the latest tech firm to abandon the dreaded stack-ranking system. On Friday, several &amp;ldquo;Affinity groups&amp;rdquo; within Amazon wrote to Bezos expressing concern about members feeling &amp;ldquo;Undeservingly pulled into the spotlight&amp;rdquo; of racial and gender controversy during the heated campaign. Bezos replied on Sunday saying that diversity is a core Amazon principle. In the case of Amazon, the regime has generated some unrest. At a website dubbed &amp;ldquo;The Former And Current Employees of Amazon,&amp;rdquo; where Amazonians can post anonymous accounts of their complaints with the company, &amp;ldquo;Performance Reviews&amp;rdquo; is one of the most popular categories. Bloomquist, the recruiter, said that phasing out stack ranking could boost Amazon&amp;rsquo;s competitiveness as an employer as others try to encroach on its talent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-finally-new-features-in-c-7-0-https-channel9-msdn-com-events-connect-2016-105&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://channel9.msdn.com/Events/Connect/2016/105&#34;&gt; So Finally, New Features in C# 7.0 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless this has changed in the release version than it seems there is a mistake within pattern matching example where the variable &amp;lsquo;i&amp;rsquo; is used outside its if level scope. If the pattern appears in the condition of an if statement, its scope is the condition and controlled statement of the if statement, but not its else clause. If this is correct than the i variable should not be in scope after the if.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-balanced-ternary-machines-of-soviet-russia-https-dev-to-buntine-the-balanced-ternary-machines-of-soviet-russia&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/buntine/the-balanced-ternary-machines-of-soviet-russia&#34;&gt; The Balanced Ternary Machines of Soviet Russia &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Perhaps the prettiest number system of all is the balanced ternary notation&amp;rdquo; - Donald E. Knuth, The Art of Computer Programming, Vol. Enter Setun, a balanced ternary computer developed in 1958 by a small team led by Nikolay Brusentsov at the Moscow State University. In its balanced form, we can think of the ternary values as being &amp;ldquo;Balanced&amp;rdquo; around the mid-point of 0. In balanced ternary, as we&amp;rsquo;re about to discover, to represent the inverse of a number we simply have to swap all +&amp;rsquo;s with -&amp;rsquo;s and vice versa. The development of balanced ternary machines has all but faded into a small footnote in the annals of computer history. For the moment at least, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that you&amp;rsquo;ll be hearing much more about balanced ternary computers in the near future. Although Setun was the first electronic device to operate on balanced ternary, it&amp;rsquo;s worth mentioning that the idea of using balanced ternary in computing devices was first popularized over 100 years before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jāas-javascript-as-a-service-http-jaasjs-com&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jaasjs.com&#34;&gt; Jāas: JavaScript as a Service &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jāas abstracts away the abstractions created by JavaScript libraries, frameworks, toolchains, compilers, and linters so you can enjoy the benefits of being on the bleeding edge without having to learn about them. You can write JavaScript like it&amp;rsquo;s 1998, and Jāas will turn it into modern type-safe, modular, and maintainable JavaScript that uses the hottest new libraries to accomplish the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-in-c-code-http-stackoverflow-com-questions-9229601-what-is-in-c-code&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/9229601/what-is-in-c-code&#34;&gt; What is &amp;ldquo;:-!!&amp;rdquo; in C code? &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another common mechanism is to call a function that isn&amp;rsquo;t defined and rely on the optimizer to compile-out the function call if your assertion is correct. In sympathy for the need for compile-time assertions, GCC 4.3 introduced the the error function attribute that allows you to extend upon this older concept, but generate a compile-time error with a message of your choosing - no more cryptic &amp;ldquo;Negative sized array&amp;rdquo; error messages! This macro will evaluate its parameter exactly once and create a compile-time error that says &amp;ldquo;I told you not to give me a five!&amp;rdquo; if the expression evaluates to five or is not a compile-time constant. So why aren&amp;rsquo;t we using this instead of negative-sized bit-fields? Alas, there are currently many restrictions of the use of statement expressions, including their use as constant initializers even if the statement expression is completely constant its self test). Hopefully, GCC will amend these shortcomings soon and allow constant statement expressions to be used as constant initializers. The challenge here is the language specification defining what is a legal constant expression. So I hope that gcc can make a constexpr functionality available as an extension via -std=gnuc99 &amp;amp; -std=gnuc11 or some such and allow its use on statement expressions et.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;google-cloud-is-50-cheaper-than-aws-https-thehftguy-wordpress-com-2016-11-18-google-cloud-is-50-cheaper-than-aws&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://thehftguy.wordpress.com/2016/11/18/google-cloud-is-50-cheaper-than-aws/&#34;&gt; Google Cloud is 50% cheaper than AWS &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, the Google entry-level instance is significantly cheaper than both AWS entry-level instances. All Google instances have significantly faster network than the equivalent AWS instances, to the point where they&amp;rsquo;re not even playing in the same league. Google is cheaper per CPU. Google CPU instances have half the memory of AWS CPU instances. Google memory instances have 15% less memory than AWS CPU instances. AWS forces you to buy a big instance to get enough SSD space whereas Google allows you to attach a SSD to a small instance. Only a very particular instance can fulfil the requirements, it comes with many cores and 4800 GB of unnecessary local SSD. The AWS bill is $4k higher than the equivalent setup on Google Cloud. We could recreate any instance from AWS on Google Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-not-change-linux-files-using-windows-apps-and-tools-https-blogs-msdn-microsoft-com-commandline-2016-11-17-do-not-change-linux-files-using-windows-apps-and-tools&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/commandline/2016/11/17/do-not-change-linux-files-using-windows-apps-and-tools/&#34;&gt; Do not change Linux files using Windows apps and tools &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DO NOT, under ANY circumstances, create and/or modify Linux files using Windows apps, tools, scripts, consoles, etc. Creating/changing Linux files from Windows will likely result in data corruption and/or damage your Linux environment requiring you to uninstall &amp;amp; reinstall your distro! If WSL can&amp;rsquo;t find Linux file metadata for a given file, it assumes the file is corrupted/damaged, and will likely fail to open/read the file correctly, causing apps, tools, etc. Several Windows tools implement different strategies to handle file updating and don&amp;rsquo;t actually edit files in-place. To work on files using both Windows and Linux tools, store &amp;amp; work on those files in your Windows filesystem, and access them from both Windows and from Bash via /mnt/&lt;drive&gt;/path. So you can easily access the same files using both Windows tools and Bash tools without having to copy files back and forth between filesystems. DO store files in your Windows filesystem that you want to create/modify using Windows tools AND Linux tools DO NOT create / modify Linux files from Windows apps, tools, scripts or consoles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;opengl-renderer-design-how-i-write-opengl-these-days-https-nlguillemot-wordpress-com-2016-11-18-opengl-renderer-design&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nlguillemot.wordpress.com/2016/11/18/opengl-renderer-design/&#34;&gt; OpenGL Renderer Design (how I write OpenGL these days) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a typical renderer, you might have a table of all the materials, a table of all the meshes, a table of all the instances of meshes, a table of all the cameras, and etc. The specifics of these tables depends on your project, so if you&amp;rsquo;re doing a skeletal animation project you would also have a table of the skeletons, instances of skeletons, and so on. Table usually have a &amp;ldquo;Primary key&amp;rdquo;, which can be used to identify each object in the table uniquely, and can also be used to efficiently lookup the object. Each mesh instance would then have a foreign key to the mesh table, and a foreign key to the transform table. I should point out that since my Scene class is implemented only in terms of plain OpenGL objects, that makes it easy for anybody to write an OpenGL renderer that reads the contents of the tables and renders them in whatever way they see fit. You might have a table for all the transforms, a table for mesh instances, and a table for meshes. To support relative transformations, I suggest creating a new table that stores the edges of the transformation tree, meaning each object in the table stores the foreign keys of two transforms: The parent and the child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 week 45 in programming</title>
      <link>http://iszlai.github.io/post/2016_week_45_in_programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 14:21:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://iszlai.github.io/post/2016_week_45_in_programming/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-guy-named-marc-andreessen-was-convinced-that-netscape-should-embed-a-programming-language-in-html-javascript-gets-written-in-10-days-flat-https-brendaneich-com-2008-04-popularity&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://brendaneich.com/2008/04/popularity/&#34;&gt; Some guy named Marc Andreessen was convinced that Netscape should embed a programming language in HTML =&amp;gt; Javascript gets written in 10 days flat. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brendan Eich convinced his pointy-haired boss at Netscape that the Navigator browser should have its own scripting language, and that only a new language would do, a new language designed and implemented in big hurry, and that no existing language should be considered for that role. As I&amp;rsquo;ve often said, and as others at Netscape can confirm, I was recruited to Netscape with the promise of &amp;ldquo;Doing Scheme&amp;rdquo; in the browser. At least client engineering management including Tom Paquin, Michael Toy, and Rick Schell, along with some guy named Marc Andreessen, were convinced that Netscape should embed a programming language, in source form, in HTML. So it was hardly a case of me selling a &amp;ldquo;Pointy-haired boss&amp;rdquo; - more the reverse. Of course, by the time I joined Netscape, and then transferred out of the server group where I had been hired based on short-term requisition scarcity games, the Oak language had been renamed Java, and Netscape was negotiating with Sun to include it in Navigator. The big debate inside Netscape therefore became &amp;ldquo;Why two languages? why not just Java?&amp;rdquo; The answer was that two languages were required to serve the two mostly-disjoint audiences in the programming ziggurat who most deserved dedicated programming languages: the component authors, who wrote in C++ or Java; and the &amp;ldquo;Scripters&amp;rdquo;, amateur or pro, who would write code directly embedded in HTML. Whether any existing language could be used, instead of inventing a new one, was also not something I decided. The diktat from upper engineering management was that the language must &amp;ldquo;Look like Java&amp;rdquo;. From the beginning, Bill grokked the idea of an easy-to-use &amp;ldquo;Scripting language&amp;rdquo; as a companion to Java, analogous to VB&amp;rsquo;s relationship to C++ in Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s platform of the mid-nineties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-you-think-you-know-c-https-medium-com-okaleniuk-so-you-think-you-know-c-8d4e2cd6f6a6-mc04v71nr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@okaleniuk/so-you-think-you-know-c-8d4e2cd6f6a6#.mc04v71nr&#34;&gt; So you think you know C? &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of programmers claim they know C. Well, it has the most famous syntax, it has been there for 44 years, and it&amp;rsquo;s not cluttered with obscure features. I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to claim that you know C. You probably learned it in college or on the go, you probably had some experience with it, you probably think that you know it through and through, because there&amp;rsquo;s not much to know. A B C D1 v2 v3 v4 v5 vYes, the right answer for every question in &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo;. C itself does not define padding attributes, so the right answer is: &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo;. So the right answer is: &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo;. The fourth looks tricky, but it&amp;rsquo;s not that hard in retrospective, since you already know that int size is not directly specified in the standard. So once again &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo; is the right answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-ve-written-a-survival-guide-for-fellow-junior-developers-check-it-out-https-medium-com-learning-new-stuff-survival-guide-for-junior-developers-d35371dd0818&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/learning-new-stuff/survival-guide-for-junior-developers-d35371dd0818&#34;&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve written a survival guide for fellow junior developers, check it out &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The switch from doing coding bootcamp projects to working on Xeneta&amp;rsquo;s full blown SaaS app with 7 other developers forced me up a pretty steep leaning curve, which I feared I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t manage to ascend, as reading source code of similar projects scared the shit out of me. If not, you&amp;rsquo;ll waste too much time banging you head against the wall. Take notesPeople are usually perfectly fine with helping others out, but you should avoid asking the same question multiple times. So whenever you get help, remember to write down the solution to next time you&amp;rsquo;re in the same situation. There are no stupid questions, but if you&amp;rsquo;ve asked the same question before, it&amp;rsquo;s a stupid one the second time you ask. Often times it&amp;rsquo;s just the terminology that&amp;rsquo;s foreign to you. Then use open time slots to learn more about the concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wind-waker-graphics-analysis-https-medium-com-gordonnl-wind-waker-graphics-analysis-a0b575a31127-p2qh15z87&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@gordonnl/wind-waker-graphics-analysis-a0b575a31127#.p2qh15z87&#34;&gt; Wind Waker Graphics Analysis &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there are two variations of oceans in Wind Waker, I find this version to be the most memorable. So to recreate this, I&amp;rsquo;ve use some compound sine curves to displace the texture lookup, as seen above on the right. An added benefit of using sine curves for displacement, is that they animate so beautifully by simply throwing time into the equation. Now, simply combine several sine curves to compound them. 6x+8.94 / 4 Here, four sine curves have been used, each with a different scale and offset. To get started, I again used the compound sine curves technique to create the rising and falling of the waves, displacing the y value of the plane&amp;rsquo;s geometry. To replicate movement around the ocean without actually moving the plane, the texture lookup can be offset by a movement vector, making the texture slide across the surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;visual-studio-for-mac-introducing-visual-studio-for-mac-https-msdn-microsoft-com-en-us-magazine-mt790182-aspx&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/magazine/mt790182.aspx&#34;&gt; Visual Studio for Mac - Introducing Visual Studio for Mac &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-interesting-story-about-self-taught-software-engineers-self-taught-software-engineers-why-open-source-is-important-to-us-https-medium-com-rocknnull-self-taught-software-engineers-why-open-source-is-important-to-us-fe2a3473a576-jm7kbh33q&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/rocknnull/self-taught-software-engineers-why-open-source-is-important-to-us-fe2a3473a576#.jm7kbh33q&#34;&gt; An interesting story about self-taught Software Engineers: &amp;ldquo;Self-taught Software Engineers: Why Open Source is important to us&amp;rdquo; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction to Open SourceAbout 13 years ago a friend introduced me to Open Source community. Why share for free the source code of my program, which I spend months developing? What if someone stole it? What if my &amp;ldquo;Competitors&amp;rdquo; use my source code to improve their products? I contributed and I improved an open source library and the open source community helped me to understand and correctly use collaborative tools like &amp;ldquo;Pull Request&amp;rdquo;. So for every open source project I am using, I am observing the source code. Thanks to open source we have access to some big projects like Mozilla Firefox for iOS or Wordpress for iOS. Being curious and observing projects like these will help you to evolve as Software Developer. Creating open source librariesAt some point I created a custom UIAlertView that I was using to my projects and I decided to make it open source. If you are active at Open Source community then you will be able to keep up with the best Software Developers or even better, to collaborate with them on a project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-riot-games-manages-docker-containers-in-production-http-engineering-riotgames-com-news-running-online-services-riot-part-ii&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://engineering.riotgames.com/news/running-online-services-riot-part-ii&#34;&gt; How Riot Games manages docker containers in production &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer to these three questions is that we need a scheduler - a service that operates at the cluster layer and executes our container strategy. The scheduler is a key component in maintaining the cluster, ensuring that containers are running in the right places, and restarting them when they die. We might want to launch a service such as Hextech Crafting, that needs six container instances to handle its load. The scheduler is responsible for finding hosts with enough memory and CPU resources to support these containers and doing whatever operations are needed to get those containers running. If one of those servers ever goes down, the scheduler is also responsible for finding a replacement host for the affected containers. They didn&amp;rsquo;t support container groups which we felt we&amp;rsquo;d need for bundling sidecar containers with many of our services. Admiral is written in Go and is compiled and packaged into a Docker container when run in a production datacenter. Moving forward, we&amp;rsquo;ll be transitioning work off Admiral and focusing on deploying DC/OS - which has become one of the leading open-source applications for scheduling container workloads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;someone-said-learning-angular-was-excruciating-so-i-put-out-a-free-course-to-make-it-less-so-https-coursetro-com-courses-8-learn-angular-2-development-with-our-free-course&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coursetro.com/courses/8/Learn-Angular-2-Development-with-our-Free-Course&#34;&gt; Someone said learning Angular was &amp;ldquo;Excruciating&amp;rdquo;, so I put out a free course to make it less so. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the world of frontend development, Angular 2 is perhaps one of the hottest topics. We&amp;rsquo;re proud to announce this 100% free course, containing both video and written content, on getting started with Angular 2. This course is perfect for those who have never touched AngularJS or Angular 2. The Angular-CLI method where you run a simply command to get your Angular 2 app up and running. We start dissecting how Angular 2 apps function at their most fundamental level. These are all of the core fundamentals that one must understand before beginning full Angular 2 apps. So if you&amp;rsquo;re ready to learn Angular 2 development today, let&amp;rsquo;s get started!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;call-for-volunteers-to-port-to-modern-opengl-in-blender-who-can-help-out-anyone-well-anyone-that-can-program-in-c-if-you-re-familiar-with-traditional-opengl-glbegin-glvertex-glend-you-ve-got-a-head-start-even-if-opengl-is-new-to-you-the-api-is-small-and-easy-to-learn-https-wiki-blender-org-index-php-dev-2-8-source-opengl-immediatemodereplacement&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.blender.org/index.php/Dev:2.8/Source/OpenGL/ImmediateModeReplacement&#34;&gt; call for volunteers to port to modern openGL in Blender. &amp;ldquo;Who can help out? Anyone! Well anyone that can program in C. If you’re familiar with traditional OpenGL (glBegin, glVertex, glEnd) you’ve got a head start. Even if OpenGL is new to you the API is small and easy to learn.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Blender code that calls legacy OpenGL functions must transition to the new API before we can throw the big switch to enable core profile. Even if OpenGL is new to you the API is small and easy to learn. Here&amp;rsquo;s a small example of legacy OpenGL followed by the new API. We&amp;rsquo;ll be drawing a triangle that has one corner with color A and the other two corners color B, the colors blending smoothly across the triangle. The old API might or might not use shaders but the new API always does. In the new API, vertex attribute values can only be set between Begin and End, and affect the current vertex. The new API has no concept of &amp;ldquo;Current color&amp;rdquo;. 8 branch has the new drawing API; all work should happen there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-intuition-in-programming-important-to-you-https-vermillionazure-com-2016-11-09-is-intuition-in-programming-important-to-you&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vermillionazure.com/2016/11/09/is-intuition-in-programming-important-to-you/&#34;&gt; Is intuition in programming important to you? &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t realize it myself a lot of times, but I&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way in changing my mindset to handle the terminology of programming ideas and make them seem natural. Do you remember the day when you didn&amp;rsquo;t understand anything of programming terminology? Today, many people do not know what a &amp;ldquo;Segmentation fault&amp;rdquo; is or why their program is crashing. Do you remember how you first grasped these basic ideas of programming? Of course, Stack Overflow has a strict policy on repeating questions that have already been answered, and an unwritten, unspoken policy on downvoting really basic questions - which I quickly learned after the fact. Who is aiming to precisely teach &amp;ldquo;How to compress methods and ideas intuitively so that they can be reconstructed and utilized at will&amp;rdquo; for basic programming concepts? For searching and understanding basic programming terminology? If you remember the time that you searched &amp;ldquo;What is the best programming language?&amp;rdquo; on the Internet, you may remember that the best answer that was given was no answer at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-list-of-almost-all-headless-web-browsers-in-existence-https-github-com-dhamaniasad-headlessbrowsers&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dhamaniasad/HeadlessBrowsers&#34;&gt; A list of (almost) all headless web browsers in existence &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rb Headless Ruby browser on top of Nokogiri and TheRubyRacer Ruby Not specified Browserjet Headless webkit browser with node. Js, with all of the pain taken out! That means you get a real browser, with a real DOM, and can do real testing! JavaScript Not specified grope A non-GUI library to represent browser environment using WebKit Framework + RubyCocoa Ruby MIT Headless Headless browser support for fast web acceptance testing in. Net.NET MIT headless browser Headless browser based on WebKit written in C++. C++ Not Specified Headless Chromium Headless Chromium is a library for running Chromium in a headless/server environment. JavaScript, Java, Ruby, PHP Apache / Commercial Selenium Selenium is a suite of tools to automate web browsers across many platforms. JavaScript Mozilla 2.0 SpecterJS A scriptable headless Internet Explorer port of PhantomJS. JavaScript MIT Splash Splash is a javascript rendering service with an HTTP API. It&amp;rsquo;s a lightweight browser with an HTTP API, implemented in Python using Twisted and QT. Any BSD-3 Clause Splinter Splinter is an open source tool for testing web applications using Python. Python - stanislaw Python headless browser testing Python Not specified trifleJS A headless Internet Explorer browser using the. Ruby MIT Webloop Scriptable, headless WebKit with a Go API. Go BSD-3 Clause WKZombie Functional headless browser for iOS using WebKit and hpple/libxml2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cracking-videogame-passwords-mike-tyson-s-punch-out-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-ap1yl-kgglg&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ap1YL_kGGlg&#34;&gt; Cracking Videogame Passwords: Mike Tyson&amp;rsquo;s Punch-Out‼ &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oauth-2-0-hack-exposes-1-billion-mobile-apps-to-account-hijacking-https-threatpost-com-oauth-2-0-hack-exposes-1-billion-mobile-apps-to-account-hijacking-121889&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://threatpost.com/oauth-2-0-hack-exposes-1-billion-mobile-apps-to-account-hijacking/121889/&#34;&gt; OAuth 2.0 Hack Exposes 1 Billion Mobile Apps to Account Hijacking &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three Chinese University of Hong Kong researchers presented at Black Hat EU last week a paper called &amp;ldquo;Signing into One Billion Mobile LApp Accounts Effortlessly with OAuth 2.0.&amp;rdquo; The paper describes an attack that takes advantage of poor OAuth 2.0 implementations and puts more than one billion apps in jeopardy. The researchers examined 600 top U.S. and Chinese Android mobile apps that use OAuth 2.0 APIs from Facebook, Google and Sina-which operates Weibo in China-and support SSO for third-party apps. The researchers found that 41.2 percent of the apps they tested were vulnerable to their attack, including popular dating, travel, shopping, hotel booking, finance, chat, music and news apps. The researchers said the apps they tested had been downloaded more than 2.4 billion times in aggregate, meaning that more than one billion are vulnerable. &amp;ldquo;After signing into the victim&amp;rsquo;s vulnerable mobile app account using our exploit, the attacker will have, in many cases, full access to the victim&amp;rsquo;s sensitive and private information which is hosted by the backend server(s) of the vulnerable mobile app,&amp;rdquo; wrote researchers Ronghai Yang, Wing Cheong Lau, and Tianyu Liu. There&amp;rsquo;s a hitch there; the researchers learned that for backwards compatibility, Facebook identifies early adopters of a mobile app using the public user ID if a user has signed into the app via OAuth before May, 2014, they&amp;rsquo;re still exposed to the attack. Further, the researchers recommend identity providers issue private identifiers rather than relying on global identifiers, and identity providers should also ramp up security testing of apps to include SSO via protocols such as OAuth 2.0 and OpenID Connect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-regex-that-only-matches-itself-http-codegolf-stackexchange-com-questions-28821-regex-that-only-matches-itself-31863-31863&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://codegolf.stackexchange.com/questions/28821/regex-that-only-matches-itself/31863#31863&#34;&gt; A Regex that only matches itself. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first time 2 should match the empty string, and the second time 2. Q2. $E/z matches 15 characters from the end. So the pattern just before the second pattern must match the first 4 or 3 characters in the first pattern, so 2.2|2)2) must match &amp;hellip;2) or &amp;hellip;2. There cannot be a trailing newline because the last character should be ). And the matched text doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain another ) before the rightmost one, so all other characters must be in the 2. The first line makes the whole expression matches exactly 188 characters since everything has a fixed length. The two times of group 1 matches 45*2 characters plus 29 times 2. If quantifier is not allowed, it is impossible because nothing which can only match one string, can match a string longer than itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-machine-learning-hard-http-ai-stanford-edu-zayd-why-is-machine-learning-hard-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ai.stanford.edu/~zayd/why-is-machine-learning-hard.html&#34;&gt; Why is machine learning &amp;lsquo;hard&amp;rsquo;? &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no doubt the science of advancing machine learning algorithms through research is difficult. Machine learning remains a hard problem when implementing existing algorithms and models to work well for your new application. The difficulty is that machine learning is a fundamentally hard debugging problem. Debugging for machine learning happens in two cases: 1) your algorithm doesn&amp;rsquo;t work or 2) your algorithm doesn&amp;rsquo;t work well enough. Luckily for machine learning algorithms you also have more signals to figure out where things went wrong. The second compounding factor that complicates machine learning debugging is long debugging cycles. Machine learning developers will run multiple experiments because the bottleneck is often the training of the algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;help-rust-make-the-most-informed-decisions-on-hkt-by-getting-involved-with-the-discussion-as-it-happens-use-cases-for-hkt-requested-https-internals-rust-lang-org-t-blog-post-series-alternative-type-constructors-and-hkt-4300&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/blog-post-series-alternative-type-constructors-and-hkt/4300&#34;&gt; Help Rust make the most informed decisions on HKT by getting involved with the discussion as it happens. Use cases for HKT requested! &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhat recently I wanted to have an Iterator impl which forced the returned Item type to be dropped before the next one could be obtained. Yes, this is usually so that the iterator can &amp;ldquo;Generate&amp;rdquo; data as it goes, using some internal storage. I don&amp;rsquo;t think you could do it with the current Iterator trait even if we had ATC. And certainly not backward compatibly. It has some kind of subtle effects on people who want to write generic code over iterators. In particular, they can no longer assume that the data they produce will outlive the iterator. Now, one of the key things that the current iterator design supports is the ability to have one iterator trait supplying &amp;amp;T, &amp;amp;mut T, or T, as you need it, iter mut(), and into iter(. In that case, the above iterator could work, so in a sense this iterator trait is strictly more expressive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-we-knew-it-was-time-to-leave-the-cloud-https-about-gitlab-com-2016-11-10-why-choose-bare-metal&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://about.gitlab.com/2016/11/10/why-choose-bare-metal/?&#34;&gt; How We Knew It Was Time to Leave the Cloud &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we found is that the cloud was not meant to provide the level of IOPS performance we needed to run an agressive system like CephFS. At a small scale, the cloud is cheaper and sufficient for many projects. It&amp;rsquo;s often sold as, &amp;ldquo;If you need to scale and add more machines, you can spawn them because the cloud is &amp;lsquo;infinite&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;. The nature of the cloud is time sharing so you still will not get the best performance. From a cost perspective, it is more economical and reliable because of how the culture of the cloud works and the level of performance we need. How we used our dashboard to understand CephFS in the cloud. Recap: What We Learned CephFS gives us more scalability and ostensibly performance but did not work well in the cloud on shared resources, despite tweaking and tuning it to try to make it work. There is a threshold of performance on the cloud and if you need more, you will have to pay a lot more, be punished with latencies, or leave the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;devfreebooks-https-devfreebooks-github-io&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://devfreebooks.github.io/&#34;&gt; DevFreeBooks &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;announcing-rust-1-13-https-blog-rust-lang-org-2016-11-10-rust-1-13-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2016/11/10/Rust-1.13.html&#34;&gt; Announcing Rust 1.13 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rust team is happy to announce the latest version of Rust, 1.13.0. Rust is a systems programming language focused on safety, speed, and concurrency. As always, you can install Rust 1.13.0 from the appropriate page on our website, and check out the detailed release notes for 1.13.0 on GitHub. We enjoyed three Rust conferences, RustConf, RustFest, and Rust Belt Rust, in short succession. Rust has gained a new operator, ?, that makes error handling more pleasant by reducing the visual noise involved. This sort of evolution is one of the great advantages of a powerful macro system: speculative extensions to the language syntax can be prototyped and iterated on without modifying the language itself, and in return, macros that turn out to be especially useful can indicate missing language features. This is a good example of the kinds of incremental, quality-of-life improvements Rust will continue to receive, polishing off the rough corners of our already-powerful base language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-ve-had-a-lot-of-problems-with-imposter-syndrome-throughout-my-career-i-finally-wrote-about-http-www-corporateprogrammer-com-blog-the-imposter-within&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.corporateprogrammer.com/blog/the-imposter-within/&#34;&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of problems with imposter syndrome throughout my career. I finally wrote about. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is still so much I don&amp;rsquo;t know, so much that I am uncertain of. Remember past successes and know that you had a role contributing to it. The beauty of our industry is that there is still so much we don&amp;rsquo;t really know. No one knows everything no matter how fanatic people can be in certain areas. We don&amp;rsquo;t know the troubles they face, what makes them really tick, what fears and weaknesses they battle out each day and what circumstantial history they have. Let&amp;rsquo;s give them a shout out based on my question &amp;ldquo;Anyone suffering from imposter syndrome lately? I&amp;rsquo;m writing a post. If you have any advice you wish to share let me know.&amp;rdquo; 75: 255-271.DOI: 10.5860/crl12-423.Techniques to deal with self-doubtTechniques to deal with uncertaintyCoping with Unknown Outcomes Corporate Programmer, Clarice Bouwer5 Ways to Let Go and Embrace an Uncertain Future Tiny Buddah, Lori Deschene7 Ways to Deal with Uncertainty So You Can Be Happier and Less Anxious Tiny Buddah, Lori DescheneComment on 5 Ways to Let Go and Embrace an Uncertain Future Disqus user drb74Cited &amp;ldquo;We are water. We evaporate, we freeze, we fall, we cool, we crash in waves, we ebb and flow, we soothe, swim and foam. A part of us looks the same to a mind that wants to condense and categorize, but in the end, we are constantly recreated anew.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;atom-1-12-released-http-blog-atom-io-2016-11-09-atom-1-12-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.atom.io/2016/11/09/atom-1-12.html&#34;&gt; Atom 1.12 released &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atom 1.12 has shipped today with another helping of fixes and improvements. The new APIs turned out to be less important than we originally thought but we&amp;rsquo;re nonetheless happy to report Atom users in all locales now get typical keyboard behavior in Atom&amp;rsquo;s default installation. The scope specificity rules for keybindings were understandably confusing lots of Atom users. A new version of the Octicons is now bundled in Atom with improvements to line-weight and sizing normalization. Keystroke Resolver API. To help address the long tail of unusual international keyboard behaviors as interpreted by Chrome, particularly on Linux, Atom 1.13 includes a custom keystroke resolver API allowing users to assign Chrome keyboard events to Atom-style keystrokes. Get all these improvements today by joining the Atom Beta Channel! Join Us! Don&amp;rsquo;t see what you were hoping for here? Join the Atom team at GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;python-for-javascript-developers-http-blog-underdog-io-post-152949056092-python-for-javascript-developers&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.underdog.io/post/152949056092/python-for-javascript-developers&#34;&gt; Python for JavaScript Developers &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To serve as a quick guide for JavaScript developers who want to get up to speed quickly with Python, but without having to learn what declaring a variable means or what a function is. Unlike JavaScript, variables in Python are always block scoped. Python is a bit more strict than JavaScript when it comes to syntax. Lists in Python are similar to arrays in JavaScript. Strings in Python are a lot like strings in JavaScript. A module in Python is simply a file that contains some Python code. Python has support for object oriented programming with classes and classical inheritance, unlike JavaScript which has prototypes with prototypal inheritance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-xy-problem-is-asking-about-your-attempted-solution-rather-than-your-actual-problem-http-xyproblem-info&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://xyproblem.info/&#34;&gt; The XY problem is asking about your attempted solution rather than your actual problem. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The XY problem is asking about your attempted solution rather than your actual problem. User wants to do X. User doesn&amp;rsquo;t know how to do X, but thinks they can fumble their way to a solution if they can just manage to do Y. User doesn&amp;rsquo;t know how to do Y either. User asks for help with Y. Others try to help user with Y, but are confused because Y seems like a strange problem to want to solve. After much interaction and wasted time, it finally becomes clear that the user really wants help with X, and that Y wasn&amp;rsquo;t even a suitable solution for X. The problem occurs when people get stuck on what they believe is the solution and are unable step back and explain the issue in full. N00b doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually want the last 3 chracters in a filename, he wants the file extensions, so why ask for the last 3 characters? &lt;n00b&gt; How can I echo the last three characters in a filename?&lt;feline&gt; If they&amp;rsquo;re in a variable: echo $ &lt;feline&gt; Why 3 characters? What do you REALLY want?&lt;feline&gt; Do you want the extension?&lt;n00b&gt; Yes.&lt;feline&gt; Then ASK FOR WHAT YOU WANT!&lt;feline&gt; There&amp;rsquo;s no guarantee that every filename will have a three-letter extension,&lt;feline&gt; so blindly grabbing three characters does not solve the problem. Can iptables do this work?Obama: Well, don&amp;rsquo;t use OS detection or version scanningAngela: I want to prevent others from knowing the type of my OS..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;zeroing-out-my-memory-does-cause-them-to-page-in-faster-after-all-https-blogs-msdn-microsoft-com-oldnewthing-20161109-00-p-94675&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20161109-00/?p=94675&#34;&gt; Zeroing out my memory does cause them to page in faster after all &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not too long ago, I answered the question &amp;ldquo;If I zero out my memory pages, does that make them page in faster?&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;No.&amp;rdquo;. Turns out that I was working from outdated information. My former colleague Adrian Oney confirms the information in the white paper shared by commenter John Doe, namely that starting in Windows Vista, the memory manager does check whether a page that is about to paged out consists entirely of zeroes. Then the memory manager turns the page into a demand-zero page rather than a page stored in the pagefile. Adrian said that he wrote the original prototype which confirmed that the extra check was worth it. &amp;ldquo;Some of this was due to apps dirtying their zero-init pages with inits to zero. Some of it was due to user mode zeroing pages for security reasons. But it was common enough to make it worthwhile.&amp;rdquo; I suspect that the increasing use of virtualization may contribute to this virtuous cycle as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fixing-cpu-frequency-scaling-issues-in-android-for-dropout-free-audio-once-and-for-all-http-superpowered-com-cpu-frequency-scaling-android&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://superpowered.com/cpu-frequency-scaling-android&#34;&gt; Fixing CPU Frequency Scaling Issues in Android for Dropout-free Audio - Once and for All &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feature is directly proportional to the CPU load. If computing demand is high, the CPU runs at maximum frequency. If the CPU runs at a low frequency, the user application may not be able to produce the new buffer within time and then users experience &amp;ldquo;Audio dropouts&amp;rdquo;. This is a excruciating problem for developers of Android apps with pro audio requirements, where CPU scaling is quite aggressive. It&amp;rsquo;s highly audible when the audio application goes into the background and Android throttles the CPU back even more, thinking that the application doesn&amp;rsquo;t need the same amount of CPU for audio, when it was in the foreground. In case you were wondering, iOS also faces this problem too, but thanks to it&amp;rsquo;s better scheduling than Android, audio dropouts are only audible when the audio app computes the next audio chunk in more than 50% of the time represented by the buffer. This class implements a &amp;ldquo;True&amp;rdquo; sustained performance mode, where the CPU runs near the maximum frequency on all CPU cores. Every example project has been updated to use SuperpoweredCPU&amp;rsquo;s sustained performance mode, which provides a for CPU frequency scalcing for every Android device on every Android version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 week 44 in programming</title>
      <link>http://iszlai.github.io/post/2016_week_44_in_programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 14:21:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://iszlai.github.io/post/2016_week_44_in_programming/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;h-264-is-magic-https-sidbala-com-h-264-is-magic&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sidbala.com/h-264-is-magic/&#34;&gt; H.264 is Magic &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we&amp;rsquo;re getting to the juicy bits! Ha puns! If you took an information theory class, you might remember information entropy. Information entropy is the number of bits required to represent some information. The fine grill on that MacBook pro has a high information content in the higher frequency components of that image. Because now, you can take that frequency domain image and then mask out the edges - discard information which will contain the information with high frequency components. The numbers represent the information entropy of that image as a fraction of the original. So there must be some way to discard color information to shed even more weight. Our frames now tiny - since we discarded most of the detail information and half of the color information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pornhub-bypasses-ad-blockers-with-websockets-http-blog-bugreplay-com-post-152579164219-pornhubdodgesadblockersusingwebsockets-utm-source-reddit-programming-utm-medium-post&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.bugreplay.com/post/152579164219/pornhubdodgesadblockersusingwebsockets?utm_source=reddit-programming&amp;amp;utm_medium=post&#34;&gt; Pornhub Bypasses Ad Blockers With WebSockets &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If WebSocket data was not visible to Chrome extensions via the webRequest API, they could not be blocked without some heavy duty hacks. Then in August 2016, an employee of the company that owns Pornhub.com started arguing against adding the WebSocket blocking capabilities to the Chrome API. Pornhub is the 63rd most visited site on the Internet according to Alexa. Watching the BugReplay browser recording, you can see a number of network requests triggered that are blocked by AdBlock: They are marked Failed in the network traffic, and if you click one to inspect the detail pane you can see the failed reason is net::ERR BLOCKED BY CLIENT. That is the error reported by Chrome when an asset is blocked from loading. The name of the domain where the WebSocket connects is &amp;ldquo;Ws://ws.adspayformy.site.&amp;rdquo; A decent joke aimed at ad blockers :). When the WebSocket loads, the browser sends a frame with a JSON encoded payload for each of the spots it has available for ads. Ad Blockers primarily work using the webRequest API, so constructing the ad by transmitting the data over the WebSocket as base64 is a pretty clever way of dodging the blocker. A contributor wrote a patch adding the ability to block WebSockets using the webRequest api. For AdBlock Plus, &amp;ldquo;The wrapper performs a dummy web request before WebSocket messages are sent/received. The extension recognizes these dummy web requests as representing a WebSocket message. It intercepts and blocks them if the corresponding WebSocket message should be blocked. The WebSocket wrapper then allows / blocks the WebSocket message based on whether the dummy web request was blocked or not.&amp;rdquo; via.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-became-a-software-engineer-https-dev-to-edemkumodzi-why-i-became-a-software-engineer&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/edemkumodzi/why-i-became-a-software-engineer&#34;&gt; Why I became a software engineer &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hear of stories of many software engineers who always knew they were going to work with computers because they started tinkering with them when they were kids. All these are very common for software engineers in the US &amp;amp; Europe but for many of us in Africa? We didn&amp;rsquo;t see a computer until we were halfway through high school. That&amp;rsquo;s how I started learning how to code seriously. Now how do I make students register online for their courses? I can&amp;rsquo;t build another windows application and expect them to download it. That&amp;rsquo;s what led to learning about web development using ASP.net. I didn&amp;rsquo;t become a software engineer because I enjoyed coding or grew up around computers or any of that. I became a software engineer because the problems I cared about solving required me to learn how to code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;utf8-everywhere-now-please-http-utf8everywhere-org&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://utf8everywhere.org/&#34;&gt; UTF8. Everywhere. Now, please. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above code point will be encoded as four code units &amp;lsquo;f0 b2 90 bf&amp;rsquo; in UTF-8, two code units &amp;lsquo;d889 dc3f&amp;rsquo; in UTF-16 and as a single code unit &amp;lsquo;0003243f&amp;rsquo; in UTF-32. For some abstract characters, there exist representations using multiple code points, in addition to the single coded character form. The abstract character  can be coded by the single code point U+01F5 latin small letter g with acute, or by the sequence &lt;U+0067 latin small letter g, U+0301 combining acute accent&gt;. A programmer might count characters as code units, code points, or grapheme clusters, according to the level of the programmer&amp;rsquo;s Unicode expertise. Working with a variable length encoding, where ASCII-inherited code points are shorter than other code points may seem like a difficult task, because encoded character boundaries within the string are not immediately known. Even in the Unicode formalism some code points correspond to coded character and some to non-characters. Counting coded characters or code points is important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;touch-id-support-for-sudo-in-macos-terminal-https-github-com-mattrajca-sudo-touchid&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mattrajca/sudo-touchid&#34;&gt; Touch ID support for &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; in MacOS Terminal &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sudo-touchid is a fork of sudo with Touch ID support on macOS. Once compiled, it will allow you to authenticate sudo commands with Touch ID in the Terminal on supported Macs. Sudo must be owned by uid 0 and have the setuid bit set. Sudo chown root:wheel sudo &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo chmod 4755 sudo. Sudo -s. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a Mac with a biometric sensor, sudo-touchid will fall back to the regular password prompt. Replacing the system&amp;rsquo;s sudo program is quite risky and requires disabling System Integrity Protection. Sudo chown root:wheel /usr/local/bin/sudo &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo chmod 4755 /usr/local/bin/sudo. Now you should be able to enter sudo in any Terminal window and authenticate with Touch ID!.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;async-await-support-landed-in-firefox-nightly-https-blog-nightly-mozilla-org-2016-11-01-async-await-support-in-firefox&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.nightly.mozilla.org/2016/11/01/async-await-support-in-firefox/&#34;&gt; async/await support landed in Firefox Nightly &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support for async/await has been added in the Nightly build from the 31st of October. Time to start removing those JavaScript transpilers from your experimental projects, and testing native browser support 😉. Here&amp;rsquo;s a demo. If your browser supports async/await natively, you will see &amp;ldquo;YES&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;visual-sudio-code-1-7-rolled-back-to-1-6-https-code-visualstudio-com-updates-v1-6-17-rollback&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/updates/v1_6#_17-rollback&#34;&gt; Visual Sudio Code 1.7 rolled back to 1.6 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you like your source code formatted each time you save? VS Code now supports &amp;ldquo;Format On Save&amp;rdquo; which will automatically pick up relevant installed formatter extensions and format the whole document on each save. Since we made VS Code available, we&amp;rsquo;ve had the debt item that some languages were implemented inside VS Code directly and they were not implemented as an extension. As you can see from the recommendations setting above, we recommend that anybody working on the VS Code codebase use the TSLint and ESLint extensions. VS Code prompts a user to install the recommended extensions when a workspace is opened for the first time. Another use case is to create a set of extensions for a particular scenario like PHP development to help a PHP developer get started with VS Code quickly. The Yeoman generator for VS Code extensions has been updated to use TypeScript version 2.0.x. If you start a new VS Code extension, simply install yeoman and the extension generator using npm install -g yo generator-code and run it using yo code. An extension would be able to configure a linter from a warning via a code action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-random-walk-through-ada-2014-i-find-myself-wondering-why-i-should-write-in-c-any-more-http-cowlark-com-2014-04-27-ada-index-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cowlark.com/2014-04-27-ada/index.html&#34;&gt; A Random Walk Through Ada (2014) – &amp;ldquo;I find myself wondering why I should write in C++ any more&amp;rdquo; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Package AnimalsPkg is type Animal is tagged null record; procedure Vocalise(creature: Animal); type Dog is new Animal with null record; procedure Vocalise(creature: Dog); end; package body AnimalsPkg is procedure Vocalise(creature: Animal) is begin Put Line(&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;); end; procedure Vocalise(creature: Dog) is begin Put Line(&amp;ldquo;Woof&amp;rdquo;); end; end;. Declare package AnimalsPkg is type Animal is abstract tagged null record; procedure Vocalise(creature: Animal) is abstract; type Dog is new Animal with null record; procedure Vocalise(creature: Dog); type Cat is new Animal with null record; procedure Vocalise(creature: Cat); end; package body AnimalsPkg is procedure Vocalise(creature: Dog) is begin Put Line(&amp;ldquo;Woof&amp;rdquo;); end; procedure Vocalise(creature: Cat) is begin Put Line(&amp;ldquo;Meow&amp;rdquo;); end; end; use AnimalsPkg; procedure Kick(creature: Animal&amp;rsquo;Class) is begin creature. Package DeadlySeriousBusinessPackage is type Object is tagged private; type ObjectRef is access Object&amp;rsquo;class; function Create return ObjectRef; private type Object is tagged null record; end; package body DeadlySeriousBusinessPackage is function Create return ObjectRef is this: ObjectRef := new Object; begin return this; end; end;. Declare task Fifo is entry Push(value: in integer); entry Pop(value: out integer); end; task body Fifo is i: integer; begin loop accept Push(value: in integer) do i := value; end; accept Pop(value: out integer) do value := i; end; end loop; end; i: integer; begin Fifo.Push(7); Fifo.Pop(i); end;. Declare task Fifo is entry Push(value: in integer); entry Pop(value: out integer); end; task body Fifo is i: integer; begin loop select accept Push(value: in integer) do i := value; end; or accept Pop(value: out integer) do value := i; end; or terminate; end select; end loop; end; i: integer; begin Fifo.Push(7); Fifo.Pop(i); end;. Declare protected Fifo is procedure Push(value: in integer); procedure Pop(value: out integer); private i: integer; end; protected body Fifo is procedure Push(value: in integer) is begin i := value; end; procedure Pop(value: out integer) is begin value := i; end; end; i: integer; begin Fifo.Push(7); Fifo.Pop(i); end;. Declare type Thing is record value: integer; end record; type ThingRef is access Thing; function NewThing return ThingRef is begin return new Thing; end; procedure FreeThing is new Ada.Unchecked Deallocation( Thing, ThingRef); p: ThingRef; begin p := NewThing; FreeThing(p); end;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;webassembly-browser-preview-http-v8project-blogspot-com-2016-10-webassembly-browser-preview-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://v8project.blogspot.com/2016/10/webassembly-browser-preview.html&#34;&gt; WebAssembly Browser Preview &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce, in tandem with Firefox and Edge, a WebAssembly Browser Preview. WebAssembly or wasm is a new runtime and compilation target for the web, designed by collaborators from Google, Mozilla, Microsoft, Apple, and the W3C WebAssembly Community Group. The binary format and JS API documents outline the binary encoding of WebAssembly and the mechanism to instantiate WebAssembly modules in the browser, respectively. V8 continues to optimize the implementation of WebAssembly in the TurboFan compiler. Js to WebAssembly under the hood so that existing asm. Js sites can reap some of the benefits of WebAssembly ahead-of-time compilation. Barring major design changes arising from community feedback, the WebAssembly Community Group plans to produce an official specification in Q1 2017, at which point browsers will be encouraged to ship WebAssembly on-by-default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-contribute-to-an-open-source-project-on-github-a-step-by-step-guide-http-blog-davidecoppola-com-2016-11-howto-contribute-to-open-source-project-on-github&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.davidecoppola.com/2016/11/howto-contribute-to-open-source-project-on-github/&#34;&gt; How to contribute to an open source project on GitHub - a step-by-step guide &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A step by step guide that will show you how to contribute to an open source project on GitHub, one of the most popular and used git repository hosting services. The way people contribute to an open source project on GitHub is using pull requests. If you decided to contribute to an open source project on GitHub it&amp;rsquo;s probably because you&amp;rsquo;ve been using that project and you found a bug or had an idea for a new feature. When deciding to contribute to an open source project make sure to check it&amp;rsquo;s still active otherwise your work might remain a pull request forever. Once you are on the main page of the project you want to contribute to look for notes and files that explain how the mantainers expect you contribute to the project. To fork a project on GitHub simply click the Fork button on the top-right corner of a project page. I hope you enjoyed this tutorial explaining how to contribute to an open source project on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deepmind-and-blizzard-to-release-starcraft-ii-as-an-ai-research-environment-deepmind-https-deepmind-com-blog-deepmind-and-blizzard-release-starcraft-ii-ai-research-environment&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://deepmind.com/blog/deepmind-and-blizzard-release-starcraft-ii-ai-research-environment/&#34;&gt; DeepMind and Blizzard to release StarCraft II as an AI research environment | DeepMind &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;minoca-os-a-new-open-source-operating-system-https-blog-minocacorp-com-minoca-os-a-new-open-source-operating-system-4bb7998df3a7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.minocacorp.com/minoca-os-a-new-open-source-operating-system-4bb7998df3a7&#34;&gt; Minoca OS: A new open source operating system &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we&amp;rsquo;re thrilled to announce that Minoca OS has gone open source. We are releasing the entirety of the Minoca OS source code under the GNU GPLv3. We&amp;rsquo;re excited to build a community of users and developers around this new operating system, and we need help. What is Minoca OS?Minoca OS is a general purpose operating system written completely from the ground up. Under the hood, Minoca contains a powerful driver model between device drivers and the kernel. We took a look at the operating systems out there, and realized it had been over 25 years since the major operating systems had been written. We wanted to see if with 25 years of hindsight and a clean slate we could create something interesting and unique in the operating systems space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;vigil-the-eternal-morally-vigilant-programming-language-https-github-com-munificent-vigil&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/munificent/vigil&#34;&gt; Vigil, the eternal morally vigilant programming language &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vigil is a very safe programming language, and an entry in the January 2013 PLT Games competition. Many programming languages claim to take testing, contracts and safety seriously, but only Vigil is truly vigilant about not allowing code that fails to pass programmatic specifications. Vigil is very similar to Python with the minor proviso that you must provide a main() function which will be automatically called for you. If a function fails to uphold what it has sworn to do, it is wrong and must be punished. When a Vigil program is executed, Vigil itself will monitor all oaths that have been made. If an oath is broken, the offending function will be duly punished. Run Vigil again and it will take care of that for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learn-latex-in-minutes-https-github-com-voluong-master-latex-in-minutes&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/VoLuong/Master-Latex-in-minutes&#34;&gt; Learn LATEX in Minutes &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LaTeX, which is pronounced «Lah-tech» or «Lay-tech», is a document preparation system for high-quality typesetting. LaTeX is just a text document, readily converted to PDF. LaTeX separates content and style. LaTeX offers a lot of functions by default, but in some situations it can come in handy to use so called packages. To add an image to the LaTeX file , you need to use figure environment and the graphicx package. Insert code into LaTeX  First method ✅. One aspect of text compiling that is of the utmost importance to programmers and developers is how to professionally insert codes into the document. LaTeX supports syntax for these languages 💬. As you can see, with the wrapper you can easily insert code without worrying about how the syntax is formatted. Multiple files in LaTeX. When we use LaTeX, we may face a problem that a document is too long to be handle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;distrusting-wosign-and-startcom-certificates-https-security-googleblog-com-2016-10-distrusting-wosign-and-startcom-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://security.googleblog.com/2016/10/distrusting-wosign-and-startcom.html&#34;&gt; Distrusting WoSign and StartCom Certificates &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;opa-a-live-memory-debugger-for-c-programs-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-pvkn9xz-xks&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pvkn9Xz-xks&#34;&gt; OPA, A live memory debugger for C programs &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-vs-code-1-7-overloaded-npmjs-org-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-12861180&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=12861180&#34;&gt; How VS Code 1.7 overloaded npmjs.org &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn&amp;rsquo;t start caching 404s for every package, and don&amp;rsquo;t plan to, because that creates annoying race conditions for fresh publishes, which is why most CDNs don&amp;rsquo;t cache 404s in the first place. There are any number of ways to fix this, and we&amp;rsquo;ll work with Microsoft to find the best one, but fundamentally you just need a more network-efficient way of finding out which type declarations exist. Might I suggest having a bloom filter containing all the existing type declaration and only querying the registry if the bloom filter reports the type declaration as a positive. Since the filter can be really small it will probably scale a lot better than a complete list of all type-declarations, and a new filter could be downloaded by the clients every now and then. Depends on the bloom filter, but for the fixed size, fixed hash functions, and other implementations in the same general vein, it would just be XOR of both of the bloom filters. Slightly different for counting filters, where something along the lines of subtraction would get you what you need. Can you speak to why it is so expensive on the NPM side to serve a 404? Would a bloom filter like another commenter mentioned be helpful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-price-of-gpl-http-bitsplitting-org-2016-10-30-the-price-of-gpl&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bitsplitting.org/2016/10/30/the-price-of-gpl/&#34;&gt; The Price Of GPL &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some will take issue with the use of strong words like &amp;ldquo;Stolen code,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Theft,&amp;rdquo; with respect to a GPL violation. Many developers seem to prefer remaining willfully oblivious to the consequences of using GPL code. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s OK for us to use GPL code anywhere, as long as we contribute back changes.&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s only a small amount of GPL code, so the license doesn&amp;rsquo;t apply. The price of GPL is fairly obvious and easy to understand, even if there is some bickering about what constitutes &amp;ldquo;linked code. &amp;rdquo; You don&amp;rsquo;t have to be a legal expert to get the gist of it: if you want to link your software with GPL code, you must also make your software&amp;rsquo;s source code available. So what am I supposed to do? Not use any GPL source code at all in any of my proprietary products? Exactly. Because the price of GPL is too much for me, and I don&amp;rsquo;t steal source code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;happy-dennis-ritchie-day-https-www-oreilly-com-ideas-dennis-ritchie-day&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oreilly.com/ideas/dennis-ritchie-day&#34;&gt; Happy Dennis Ritchie Day! &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s just C. Dennis was also half of the team that created Unix, which in some form or other runs all the machines at Google&amp;rsquo;s data centers and probably at most other server farms. Most web servers run above Unix kernels; most non-Microsoft web browsers run above Unix kernels in some form, even in many phones. In the late 1970s, Dennis joined with Steve Johnson to port Unix to the Interdata. Unix, in the unusual position of being written in a &amp;ldquo;High-level language,&amp;rdquo; could be made to run on a machine other than the PDP-11. The hardware didn&amp;rsquo;t matter any more, since it all ran Unix. Cheap hardware meant cheap Unix installations; we all won. If Unix hadn&amp;rsquo;t been ported to the Interdata, the Internet, if it even existed, would be a very different place today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-stackoverflow-import-quick-sort-https-github-com-drathier-stack-overflow-import&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/drathier/stack-overflow-import&#34;&gt; from stackoverflow import quick_sort &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you ever feel like all you&amp;rsquo;re doing is copy/pasting from Stack Overflow? From stackoverflow import quick sort will go through the search results of [python] quick sort looking for the largest code block that doesn&amp;rsquo;t. Syntax error in the highest voted answer from the highest voted question. Code, it checks the next highest voted answer for code blocks. &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; from stackoverflow import quick sort, split into chunks &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; print(quick sort. Chunk(&amp;ldquo;Very good chunk func&amp;rdquo; ) &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; print(&amp;ldquo;Gotta take a break&amp;rdquo;) gotta take a break &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; from time import time &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; t1 = time() &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; from stackoverflow import time delay &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; print(&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s enough, let&amp;rsquo;s continue coding&amp;rdquo;, time() - t1) that&amp;rsquo;s enough, let&amp;rsquo;s continue coding 5.7283220291137695 &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; print(&amp;ldquo;I wonder who made split into chunks&amp;rdquo;, split into chunks. This module is PSF-licensed as I blatantly copied multiple lines of code from the Python standard library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;h-265-is-weaponized-science-https-sonnati-wordpress-com-2014-06-20-h265-part-i-technical-overview&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sonnati.wordpress.com/2014/06/20/h265-part-i-technical-overview/&#34;&gt; H.265 is Weaponized Science &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each CU can be recursively splitted in Transform Units with the same quad-tree approach used in CTBs. Differently from AVC that used mainly a 4×4 transform and occasionally an 8×8 transform, HEVC has several transform sizes: 32×32, 16×16, 8×8 and 4×4. The adaptive nature of CBT, CU and TU partitions plus the higher accuracy plus the larger transform size are among the most important features of HEVC and the reason of the performance improvement compared to AVC. HEVC implements a sofisticated scan order and coefficient signaling scheme that improves signaling efficiency. HEVC drops also the support for MBAFF or similar techniques to code interlaced video. The merge mode is similar, the main difference is that the candidates list is calculated from neighboring MV and is not added to a delta MV. It is the equivalent of &amp;ldquo;Skip&amp;rdquo; mode in AVC. Similarly to AVC, HEVC specifies motion vectors in &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-pel, but uses an 8-tap filter for luma and a 4-tap &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt;-pel filter for chroma. CABAC in HEVC is almost identical to CABAC in AVC with minor changes and simplifications to allow a parallel decoding. Since HEVC decoding is much more complex than AVC, several technique to allow a parallal decoding have been implemented. The adaptive subdivision of picture in prediction areas, the use of advanced intra-prediction, inter-prediction and bigger transform sizes can absolutely guarantee, in the long term, a considerably higher efficiency of HEVC compared to AVC. But the complexity of the encoding is really much higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-silent-majority-of-experts-http-prog21-dadgum-com-143-html-0&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://prog21.dadgum.com/143.html?0&#34;&gt; The Silent Majority of Experts &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forth, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only person frustrated by the lack of people doing interesting things with the language. Elizabeth Rather, co-founder of Forth, Inc., offered the following explanation: there are people solving real problems with Forth, but they don&amp;rsquo;t hang-out in the newsgroup. There were a number of game developers with public faces in the 1990s, but the key people responsible for the original version of The Need for Speed, released in 1994, remained unknown and behind the scenes. Yes, there are many people who blog and otherwise publicly discuss development methodologies and what they&amp;rsquo;re working on, but there are even more people who don&amp;rsquo;t. Other people are working on commercial products and can&amp;rsquo;t divulge the inner workings of their code. All we&amp;rsquo;re seeing is an intersection of the people working on interesting things and who like to write about it-and that&amp;rsquo;s not the whole story. Your time may better spent getting in there and trying things rather than reading about what other people think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;scala-2-12-0-is-now-available-http-www-scala-lang-org-news-2-12-0&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scala-lang.org/news/2.12.0&#34;&gt; Scala 2.12.0 is now available &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scala 2.12.0 is the result of merging over 500 pull requests out of about 600 received PRs. The contributions to 2.12.x over the last 2 years were split as 64/32/4 between the Scala team at Lightbend, the community and EPFL. The new encodings of traits, lambdas and lazy vals were developed in fruitful collaboration with the Dotty team at EPFL. Binary compatibility. Since Scala 2.10, minor releases of Scala are binary compatible with each other. Scala 2.12 standardizes on the &amp;ldquo;GenBCode&amp;rdquo; back end, which emits code more quickly because it directly generates bytecode from Scala compiler trees, while the previous back end used an intermediate representation called &amp;ldquo;ICode&amp;rdquo;. The Scala distribution is built using -opt:l:classpath, which improves the performance of the Scala compiler by roughly 5% compared to a non-optimized build. The Java 8 compatibility module for Scala has received an overhaul for Scala 2.12. Even though interoperability of Java 8 SAMs and Scala functions is now baked into the language, this module provides additional convenience for working with Java 8 SAMs. Java 8 streams support was also added during the development cycle of Scala 2.12. Releases are available for both Scala 2.11 and Scala 2.12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-hardware-development-is-hard-part-1-verilog-is-terrible-https-danluu-com-why-hardware-development-is-hard&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://danluu.com/why-hardware-development-is-hard/&#34;&gt; Why hardware development is hard, part 1: Verilog is terrible &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why hardware development is hard, part 1: Verilog is weird Why hardware development is hard, part 1: Verilog is weird. How is it possible that a reasonable description of something in Verilog turns into something completely wrong in hardware? You can think of hardware as some state, with pure functions connecting the state elements. To write Verilog that will produce correct hardware, you have to first picture the hardware you want to produce. We hardware folks are so used to the vast majority of legal Verilog constructs producing unsynthesizable garbage that we don&amp;rsquo;t find it the least bit surprising that you not only do you not get compile-time errors, you don&amp;rsquo;t even get run-time errors, from writing naive Verilog code. With hardware, we train up a new generation of people who think that Verilog is as productive as any language could be every few years! I won&amp;rsquo;t even get into how Verilog is so inexpressive that many companies use an ad hoc tool to embed a scripting language in Verilog or generate Verilog from a scripting language. It&amp;rsquo;s not as high level, but it&amp;rsquo;s the only hardware description language with a modern type system that I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to discuss with hardware folks without people objecting that Haskell is a bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mercurial-4-0-has-been-released-https-www-mercurial-scm-org-wiki-whatsnew-mercurial-4-0-282016-11-1-29&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mercurial-scm.org/wiki/WhatsNew#Mercurial_4.0_.282016-11-1.29&#34;&gt; Mercurial 4.0 has been released &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rollback: add a config knob for entirely disabling the command subrepo: use unset instead of env -u to fix test on BSDs.templates: add support for filelog webcommand in json style templates: add support for filerevision webcommand in json style templates: add support for search webcommand in json style templates: add support for summary webcommand in json style update: fix bare -clean to work on new branch. Notify: do not load style file if template is specified record: deprecate the extension registrar: add templatefilter to mark a function as template filter registrar: add templatefunc to mark a function as template function registrar: add templatekeyword to mark a function as template keyword registrar: remove useless base classes remove: add progress support remove: fix -force option help description. Batchget: add support for backing up files builddeb: add -distid option to specify Distributor ID changegroup: introduce cg3, which has support for exchanging treemanifests changelog: add a new method to get files modified by a changeset checkunknownfiles: make control flow clearer crecord: edit during hg crecord should preserve cursor position. Match: add option to return line and lineno from readpattern mercurial: pass ui to extensions. Files() in conditions commit: improve -close-branch documentation commit: mark internal-only option commit: no longer allow empty commit with the &amp;lsquo;force&amp;rsquo; argument config: give it an includepaths option for looking for config files files: recurse into subrepos automatically with an explicit path import-checker: add xargs like mode import-checker: don&amp;rsquo;t treat modules as relative one if not found import-checker: exclude mercurial packages installed into the system path import-checker: loop to get list of locally defined modules at first import: cross-reference patch. Allowemptycommit to allow empty commits log: add a status template patch: add &amp;lsquo;extra&amp;rsquo; argument to makememctx patch: add fuzz config flag. Subrepo: add &amp;lsquo;cat&amp;rsquo; support for git subrepos subrepo: add basic support to hgsubrepo for the files command subrepo: add include/exclude support for diffing git subrepos subrepo: add status support for ignored and clean files in git subrepos subrepo: change arguments of abstractsubrepo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 week 43 in programming</title>
      <link>http://iszlai.github.io/post/2016_week_43_in_programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 22:08:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://iszlai.github.io/post/2016_week_43_in_programming/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;applying-the-linus-tarvolds-good-taste-coding-requirement-https-medium-com-bartobri-applying-the-linus-tarvolds-good-taste-coding-requirement-99749f37684a-h5uuz43ge&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@bartobri/applying-the-linus-tarvolds-good-taste-coding-requirement-99749f37684a#.h5uuz43ge&#34;&gt; Applying the Linus Tarvolds &amp;ldquo;Good Taste&amp;rdquo; Coding Requirement &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the best of my ability to discern, the crux of the &amp;ldquo;Good taste&amp;rdquo; requirement is the elimination of edge cases, which tend to reveal themselves as conditional statements. Below is an algorithm I wrote to initialize the points along the edge of a grid, which is represented as a multidimensional array: grid[rows][cols]. Again, the purpose of this code was to only initialize the values of the points that reside on the edge of the grid - so only the top row, bottom row, left column, and right column. To accomplish this I initially looped over every point in the grid and used conditionals to test for the edges. Complexity - The use 4 conditional statements inside 2 embedded loops seems overly complex. It was only a slight improvement in complexity, but a large improvement in performance, because it only performed 256 loop iterations, one for each point along the edge. For This code initializes four different edge points for each loop iteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-official-java-9-will-support-ahead-of-time-compilation-but-only-64-bit-linux-initially-http-openjdk-java-net-jeps-295&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://openjdk.java.net/jeps/295&#34;&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s official: Java 9 will support ahead-of-time compilation (but only 64-bit Linux initially) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AOT compilation of any other JDK module, or of user code, is experimental. During AOT compilation a fingerprint for each class is generated and stored in the data section of the shared library. In these cases, AOT compilation needs be done on the entire application and is thus experimental in JDK 9. The system should have installed libelf to allow generation of AOT shared libraries as result of AOT compilation. AOT compilation should be executed on the same system or a system with the same configuration on which AOT code will be used by Java application. For the initial release in JDK 9 the only supported module for AOT compilation will be java. The same Java run-time configuration should be used during AOT compilation and execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;android-can-be-rooted-using-recently-discovered-linux-vulnerability-http-arstechnica-com-security-2016-10-android-phones-rooted-by-most-serious-linux-escalation-bug-ever&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arstechnica.com/security/2016/10/android-phones-rooted-by-most-serious-linux-escalation-bug-ever/&#34;&gt; Android can be rooted using recently discovered Linux vulnerability &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s extremely easy to exploit, making it one of the worst privilege-elevation flaws ever to hit the open-source OS. Independent security researcher David Manouchehri told Ars that this proof-of-concept code that exploits Dirty Cow on Android gets devices close to root. With a few additional lines, Manouchehri&amp;rsquo;s code provides persistent root access on all five of the Android devices he has tested. &amp;ldquo;From what I can tell, in theory it should be able to root every device since Android 1.0. Android 1.0 started on [Linux] kernel [version] 2.6.25, and this exploit has been around since 2.6.22.&amp;ldquo;. Both of the exploits allow end users to root Android phones so they have capabilities such as tethering that are often restricted by individual manufacturers or carriers. Just as Dirty Cow has allowed untrusted users or attackers with only limited access to a Linux server to dramatically elevate their control, the flaw can allow shady app developers to evade Android defenses that cordon off apps from other apps and from core OS functions. The reliability of Dirty Cow exploits and the ubiquity of the underlying flaw makes it an ideal malicious root trigger, especially against newer devices running the most recent versions of Android. Dirty Cow came to light a few days before the release of a separate rooting method for Android devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;happiness-is-a-boring-stack-http-www-expatsoftware-com-articles-happiness-is-a-boring-stack-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.expatsoftware.com/Articles/happiness-is-a-boring-stack.html&#34;&gt; Happiness is a Boring Stack &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a fun place, and a good way to keep up to date on all the new tech that us developer folk seem to need to know about. Yeah, sure, Node.js with tons of functional stuff mixed in pulling from a NoSQL store and React on the front end. For my own stuff, there&amp;rsquo;s no way I&amp;rsquo;d use any of that crap. This stuff is my proper income stream, and the most important thing is that it works. It means I can, among other things, pick up a full-time development gig to sock away some extra runway, take off and go backpacking around the world, or better still, build yet another rent-paying product without having to spend a significant amount of time keeping the old stuff alive. It seems like on a lot of stacks, keeping the server alive, patched and serving webpages is a part-time job in itself. The less effort you need to spend on maintenance, the more pace you can keep going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;parsing-json-is-a-minefield-http-seriot-ch-parsing-json-php&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://seriot.ch/parsing_json.php&#34;&gt; Parsing JSON is a Minefield 💣 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Range and Precision - What about numbers with a huge amount of digits? According to RFC 7159, &amp;ldquo;A JSON parser MUST accept all texts that conform to the JSON grammar&amp;rdquo;. A JSON parser MUST accept all texts that conform to the JSON grammar. Independently from how parsers should behave, I wanted to observe how they actually behave, so I picked several JSON parsers and set up things so that I could feed them with my test files. The parsers are generally wrapped so that the process returns 0 in case of success, 1 in case of parsing error, yet another status in case of crash, a 5-second delay being considered as a timeout. Parsing should have succeeded but failedparsing should have failed but succeededresult undefined, parsing succeededresult undefined, parsing failedCrashTimeout. A JSON parser transforms a JSON text into another representation. I wrote yet another JSON parser which will parse or reject JSON document according to my understanding of RFC 7159.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-get-fired-using-switch-statements-statement-expressions-http-blog-robertelder-org-switch-statements-statement-expressions&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.robertelder.org/switch-statements-statement-expressions/&#34;&gt; How to Get Fired Using Switch Statements &amp;amp; Statement Expressions &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One extremely unmaintainable and bug-ridden technique for C programming involves using both switch statements and statement expressions together. In this article, we will discuss how you can leverage switch statements and statement expressions to produce C code that is so difficult to understand, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to look at the assembly to figure out what it does. After branching to that label nothing special happens related to the fact that you&amp;rsquo;re inside a switch statement and the code will just keep executing whatever machine instructions come next. The one exception is, of course, the break statement which will jump to the point after the switch statement body. Here is an equivalent version of the switch statement written above using only ifs and gotos. The switch statement effectively just gives us a convenient way to implement the goto statements that would be necessary to either jump to the start of the coroutine, or the point just after the coroutine returns. Regular ole expression &lt;em&gt;/ int i = 0; /&lt;/em&gt; Fancy new statement expression */ int j =;. You might ask &amp;ldquo;Why would you ever want to do such a thing?&amp;rdquo; There are a number of different answers and many of them are related to convenience: One use case is concerned with ensuring that expression statement side-effects are only evaluated once in the case of a function macro that may cause the expression to appear multiple times in the function macro body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;patent-judge-issues-opinion-declaring-all-software-patents-bad-https-www-techdirt-com-articles-20161005-15280135720-prominent-pro-patent-judge-issues-opinion-declaring-all-software-patents-bad-shtml&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20161005/15280135720/prominent-pro-patent-judge-issues-opinion-declaring-all-software-patents-bad.shtml&#34;&gt; Patent Judge Issues Opinion Declaring All Software Patents Bad &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This latest ruling, from the very court that upended things nearly two decades ago in declaring software much more broadly patentable than anyone believed, may now be the nail in the coffin on software patents in the US. The headline, of course, is that the patents that Intellectual Ventures used against anti-virus firms Symantec and Trend Micro, were bunk, because they did not cover patent eligible subject matter. The part that has everyone chattering is the concurring opinion by Judge Haldane Mayer, that says it&amp;rsquo;s time to face facts: Alice killed software patents. In Support of Respondents, Alice, 134 S. Ct. 2347, 2014 WL 828047, at *6-7; Mark A. Lemley, Software Patents and the Return of Functional Claiming, 2013 Wis. L. Rev. 905, 935 (&amp;ldquo;Software patents &amp;hellip; have created a large number of problems for the industry, particularly for the most innovative and productive companies&amp;hellip;. [T]he existence of a vibrant open source community suggests that innovation can flourish in software absent patent protection.&amp;rdquo; (footnote omitted ; Wendy Seltzer, Software Patents and/or Software Development, 78 Brook. Mayer goes even further in this discussing four separate problems with the whole concept of software patents, including the fact that the scope of the patents greatly exceeds the importance of what they disclose. The third problem he discusses is the fact that the system is overwhelmed with software patents, &amp;ldquo;Most of which are replete with broad, functional claims&amp;rdquo; which makes it &amp;ldquo;Virtually impossible to innovate in any technological field without being ensnared by the patent thicket.&amp;rdquo; Nicely put. From there, he suggests that the courts should just stop punting on the issue and declare software patents dead: Declaring that software implemented on a generic computer falls outside of section 101 would provide muchneeded clarity and consistency in our approach to patent eligibility. It would end the semantic gymnastics of trying to bootstrap software into the patent system by alleging it offers a &amp;ldquo;Specific method of filtering Internet content,&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;. The opinion is a great read overall - and it&amp;rsquo;s the kind of arguments that plenty of folks in and around tech and software patents have been making for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-taste-of-haskell-https-hookrace-net-blog-a-taste-of-haskell&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hookrace.net/blog/a-taste-of-haskell/&#34;&gt; A Taste of Haskell &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The error message tells us that the list is assumed to be a list of booleans because of the final value. If the list has more than one element, we remove the first element of the list and recursively call last&amp;rsquo; on the rest of the list. The length of a list with more than 0 elements is 1 plus the length of the rest of the list. Map&amp;rsquo; f [] = []. The base case is easy: When we get an empty list passed, the result is also an empty list. Finally we recurse with the rest of the list, until we reach the base case for the empty list. While working with lists in Haskell you might wonder what happens if we never reach the base case? We have lazy evaluation in Haskell, which tells us that a data structure is only evaluated when it&amp;rsquo;s actually needed. The second parameter is a list of values of type a, the third parameter is a list of values of type b and finally a list of type c is returned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-became-hackerrank-1-in-two-hours-http-williampross-com-became-hackerrank-1-two-hours&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://williampross.com/became-hackerrank-1-two-hours/&#34;&gt; How I Became HackerRank #1 In Two Hours &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My ranking on Hacker Rank is #1 for Java programming and it only took me two hours. After earning a top ranking for Java developers globally, Furlong was hired by JPMorgan Chase &amp;amp; Co. in December for its two-year technology training program. Much of the time I spent trying to solve problems on Hacker Rank was battling with standard in, rather than solving problems. Due to these limitations, the programmer is often spending half the time fighting with the Hacker Rank website, rather than learning. First of all, Hacker Rank only &amp;ldquo;Teaches&amp;rdquo; the basic Java language features. A programmer&amp;rsquo;s merit has never relied on rankings, and there is no reason to start now. If a person is claiming to be a top ranked programmer from Hacker Rank you should know this person is likely a fraud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;freeing-my-tablet-android-hacking-sw-and-hw-https-www-thanassis-space-android-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thanassis.space/android.html&#34;&gt; Freeing my tablet (Android hacking, SW and HW) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 ttsiod ttsiod 21 Oct 8 23:11 userdata -&amp;gt; /dev/block/mmcblk0p32 Golly gee, Mr Google, that&amp;rsquo;s a lot of partitions. I do believe though that when you do this, the tablet is supposed to be wiped automatically&amp;hellip; since by allowing booting of a custom image, an external entity can pretty much gather every data residing inside the tablet - and completely violate your privacy. Rc drwxr-xr-x 2 ttsiod ttsiod 4096 Oct 23 08:30 proc -rw-r-r- 1 ttsiod ttsiod 3138 Oct 23 08:30 property contexts drwxr-xr-x 3 ttsiod ttsiod 4096 Oct 23 08:30 res drwxr-x&amp;ndash; 2 ttsiod ttsiod 4096 Oct 23 08:30 sbin -rw-r-r- 1 ttsiod ttsiod 746 Oct 23 08:30 seapp contexts -rw-r-r- 1 ttsiod ttsiod 76 Oct 23 08:30 selinux version -rw-r-r- 1 ttsiod ttsiod 177701 Oct 23 08:30 sepolicy -rw-r-r- 1 ttsiod ttsiod 10468 Oct 23 08:30 service contexts drwxr-xr-x 2 ttsiod ttsiod 4096 Oct 23 08:30 sys drwxr-xr-x 2 ttsiod ttsiod 4096 Oct 23 08:30 system -rw-r-r- 1 ttsiod ttsiod 8349 Oct 23 08:30 ueventd. So I went back to that Over-The-Air update&amp;hellip;. host$ ls -l total 803592 drwxr-xr-x 2 ttsiod ttsiod 4096 Oct 21 01:22./ drwxr-xr-x 6 ttsiod ttsiod 4096 Sep 25 23:34./ -rw-rw-r- 1 ttsiod ttsiod 822861864 Aug 7 2015 UL-K01E-WW-12.16.1.12-user. We CAN boot our own boot images on the tablet, but ASUS keeps a note somewhere: &amp;ldquo;This is a bad person, booting his own boot image. We will no longer boot for him normally.&amp;rdquo; We CAN clear our record afterwards and make the tablet &amp;ldquo;Normal&amp;rdquo; again. this took me ages to find and to manage to compile properly - Joshua Brindle provides the source code of sepolicy-inject; a tool that allowed me to tell Android that the SELinux policy I want&amp;hellip;. host$ ls -l drwxr-xr-x 2 ttsiod ttsiod 4096 Oct 22 16:05./ drwxr-xr-x 4 ttsiod ttsiod 4096 Oct 4 2015./ -rw-r-r- 1 ttsiod ttsiod 349 Oct 22 15:42 Makefile -rw-r-r- 1 ttsiod ttsiod 1088 Jul 17 2013 README.txt -rw-r-r- 1 ttsiod ttsiod 5851 Jul 17 2013 sepolicy-inject. God knows what else - the GPS, etc :-(. I have to go back to my original plan - boot from the pristine boot image burned in the tablet, and become root ONLY through modifications to my /system partition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-was-it-like-programming-skyrim-stream-with-former-bethesda-lead-programmer-brett-douville-http-www-gamasutra-com-view-news-284447-what-was-it-like-programming-skyrim&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamasutra.com/view/news/284447/What_was_it_like_programming_Skyrim&#34;&gt; &amp;ldquo;What was it like programming Skyrim?&amp;rdquo; - Stream with former Bethesda Lead programmer Brett Douville &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been five years since The Elder Scrolls: Skyrim launched, and since then the way open-world games are made has changed so much. Bethesda Softworks has gone on to release Fallout 4, and companies like Ubisoft and CD Projekt Red have built their own templates for creating vast, open game spaces that rival the size of Bethesda&amp;rsquo;s fifth Elder Scrolls RPG. But despite how far open-world games have come, we at Gamasutra were curious, what was it like working on Skyrim? With the release of Skyrim&amp;rsquo;s special edition that brings the game to PS4 and Xbox One, we decided to invite former Bethesda Softworks lead programmer Brett Douville in for a conversation about programming the game. As seen above, the chat was particularly illuminating, since as Douville explained, the best language a programmer can know isn&amp;rsquo;t any coding language, but as he puts it &amp;ldquo;English&amp;rdquo;-meaning just having the ability to communicate with other team members and translate game design concepts into code and back. It turns out that even while Skyrim proved to be a huge programming challenge, it was also a lesson for Douville and his colleagues to just figure out how to take care of themselves and work together as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;picat-the-programming-language-you-ve-never-heard-about-wins-10k-prize-at-media-lab-summit-http-bcexcelsior-com-computer-programming-language-wins-grand-prize-at-media-lab-summit&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bcexcelsior.com/computer-programming-language-wins-grand-prize-at-media-lab-summit/&#34;&gt; Picat, the programming language you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard about, wins 10K prize at Media Lab Summit &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A team of two students and one professor from Brooklyn College won the grand prize of $10,000 at the NYC Media Lab Summit at Columbia University on Sept. 22. Computer Science Professor Neng-Fa Zhou, first-year graduate student Jie Mei, and programmer Jonathan Fruhman brought home the prize for their demo of a programming language called Picat. &amp;ldquo;Picat is a multi-paradigm programming language aimed for general-purpose applications, which means theoretically it can be used for everything in life,&amp;rdquo; said Mei. Mei, on the other hand, worked on programming during his years in college. Mei, along with his teammates at the University of Michigan, finished a project called Creative AI. They applied a neuro-linguistic programming concept &amp;ldquo;To develop models of a music artist&amp;rsquo;s lyrics so that the model would receive lyric data as input and ultimately generates new random lyrics in the style of that artist,&amp;rdquo; said Mei. Even though both Mei and Zhou have completed and worked on many successful projects, they were surprised to learn they won the grand prize. According to Picat&amp;rsquo;s website, the language incorporates the features of many other computer languages so users can solve problems more easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nim-0-15-2-released-http-nim-lang-org-news-e028-version-0-15-2-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nim-lang.org/news/e028_version_0_15_2.html&#34;&gt; Nim 0.15.2 released &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce that the latest release of Nim, version 0.15.2, is now available! As always, you can grab the latest version from the downloads page. This release is a pure bugfix release fixing the most pressing issues and regressions of 0.15.0. The list below has been generated based on the commits in Nim&amp;rsquo;s git repository. As such it lists only the issues which have been closed via a commit, for a full list see this link on Github. &amp;ldquo; Fixed &amp;ldquo;Internal error when passing parameter proc inside. Gcsafe closure&amp;rdquo; Fixed &amp;ldquo;Upcoming asyncdispatch doesn&amp;rsquo;t compile with C++ backend on OS X&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;trick-or-treat-programs-runnable-in-two-different-languages-and-that-print-trick-in-one-language-and-treat-in-the-other-http-codegolf-stackexchange-com-questions-97472-trick-or-treat-polyglot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://codegolf.stackexchange.com/questions/97472/trick-or-treat-polyglot&#34;&gt; Trick OR Treat: programs runnable in two different languages and that print &amp;ldquo;Trick&amp;rdquo; in one language and &amp;ldquo;Treat&amp;rdquo; in the other &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The types t and t1 don&amp;rsquo;t matter as the arguments aren&amp;rsquo;t used in the function body. The IO-action type results from print&amp;rdquo;Treat&amp;rdquo;, which prints &amp;ldquo;Treat&amp;rdquo; to StdOut. It&amp;rsquo;s type is val :: t -&amp;gt; which is executed when the program is run. To determine whether main equals putStr&amp;rdquo;Trick&amp;rdquo;, both sides have to be evaluated and both must have the same type, as SML is statically typed. Print has the type string -&amp;gt; unit, so putStr has the type a -&amp;gt; unit and therefore putStr&amp;rdquo;Trick&amp;rdquo; has just type unit. In order to be well-typed, main must have type unit too. So first the types of putStr and main are shown, then the expressions gets evaluated causing treat to be printed, then the value of the expression (true as both sides of = are ( is bound to the implicit result variable it which is then also displayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-printf-unix-021-six-012-0-unix-have-fun-0x60-http-faehnri-ch-have-fun&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://faehnri.ch/have-fun/&#34;&gt; main(){printf(&amp;amp;unix[&amp;rdquo;\021%six\012\0&amp;rdquo;], (unix)[&amp;ldquo;have&amp;rdquo;]+&amp;ldquo;fun&amp;rdquo;-0x60);} &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IOCCC was inspired by Steve Bourne when he decided touse the C preprocessor to write his Unix shell in a syntax of C more like Algol-68 with explicit end statement cues where you have code like. IF *s2++ == 0 THEN return(0); FI. As Expert C says about this kind of code;. Is unix a keyword? Is it somehow printing the variable name? Searching the gcc source code, I find that it&amp;rsquo;s a run-time target specification. So unix wasn&amp;rsquo;t the name of an array variable, but how does 1[] work? I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this before and it&amp;rsquo;s one of my favorite facts about C. C has origins in the langauge BCPL. From Dr. Martin Richards, creator BCPL;. The monodic indirection operator ! takes a pointer as it&amp;rsquo;s argument and returns the contents of the word pointed to. If v is a pointer !(v+I) will access the word pointed to by v+I. The dyadic version of ! is defined so that v!i = !(v+I). V!i behaves like a subscripted expression with v being a one dimensional array and I being an integer subscript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happens-when-your-laptop-screen-breaks-at-the-himalayas-http-tombh-co-uk-when-your-screen-breaks-in-the-himalayas&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tombh.co.uk/when-your-screen-breaks-in-the-himalayas&#34;&gt; What happens when your laptop screen breaks at the Himalayas &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deep-learning-papers-reading-roadmap-https-github-com-songrotek-deep-learning-papers-reading-roadmap&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/songrotek/Deep-Learning-Papers-Reading-Roadmap&#34;&gt; Deep Learning papers reading roadmap &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading above papers, you will have a basic understanding of the Deep Learning history, the basic architectures of Deep Learning model(including CNN, RNN, LSTM) and how deep learning can be applied to image and speech recognition issues. &amp;ldquo;Learning to learn by gradient descent by gradient descent.&amp;rdquo; arXiv preprint arXiv:1606. &amp;ldquo;Unsupervised representation learning with deep convolutional generative adversarial networks.&amp;rdquo; arXiv preprint arXiv:1511. &amp;ldquo;Neural Machine Translation by Jointly Learning to Align and Translate.&amp;rdquo; arXiv preprint arXiv:1409. &amp;ldquo;Reinforcement learning neural Turing machines.&amp;rdquo; arXiv preprint arXiv:1505. &amp;ldquo;Dueling network architectures for deep reinforcement learning.&amp;rdquo; arXiv preprint arXiv:1511. &amp;ldquo;One-shot Learning with Memory-Augmented Neural Networks.&amp;rdquo; arXiv preprint arXiv:1605.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-fast-cloc-replacement-written-in-rust-https-github-com-cgag-loc&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cgag/loc&#34;&gt; A fast cloc replacement written in rust &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s another rust code counting tool called tokei, loc is ~2-10x faster than tokei, depending on how many files are being counted. I can count my 400k file src directory in just under 7 seconds with loc, in a 1m14s with tokei, and I&amp;rsquo;m not even willing to try with cloc. Loc: 1.09 seconds tokei: 5.3 seconds cloc: 1 minute, 50 seconds Installation. For anyone familiar with Rust there&amp;rsquo;s cargo install loc. Fortran has a rule that comments must start with the first character of a line. X = &amp;ldquo;/* I haven&amp;rsquo;t slept for 10 days because that would be too long */&amp;ldquo;;. loc counts the first line and last lines correctly as code, but the middle lines will be incorrectly counted as comments. This project contains code from Tokei by Aaronepower and ripgrep by BurntSushi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-tdd-ing-your-frontend-feels-pointless-https-engineering-haus-com-why-tdding-your-frontend-feels-pointless-5f710fea7325-nvs9bxmb5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.haus.com/why-tdding-your-frontend-feels-pointless-5f710fea7325#.nvs9bxmb5&#34;&gt; Why TDD’ing your frontend feels pointless &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working on the frontend of our application however, I found TDD difficult to do and less satisfying than with backend code. The first two points above I will very much take blame for and not fault TDD, especially given my comparative inexperience with frontend coding at the beginning of our project. Humans are hard to predict So this brings us to the biggest problem with TDD and frontend code. As an aside, folks who are just getting started in coding and/or not used to TDD who don&amp;rsquo;t understand where it shines often don&amp;rsquo;t see the point of using it. What is the frontend and how do we test it then?So up to this point, I&amp;rsquo;ve used the word frontend to describe a thing that&amp;rsquo;s hard to TDD. If you&amp;rsquo;re a web developer though, do not think that everything you have running in your user&amp;rsquo;s browser is hard to test or is even frontend code. Not everything running in the browser is hard to test or even frontend codeBecause a lot of business logic running in a browser or other client is so close to the UI, you may get the impression that it&amp;rsquo;s all hard to use TDD with. Tell me I&amp;rsquo;m wrong and show me the wayI love practicing TDD. I would love to be wrong about this, so please share your experiences below about how you have figured out how to do TDD with user interfaces that doesn&amp;rsquo;t end up with throwing away most code immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;twenty-years-later-i-wrote-a-tetris-again-https-blog-levit-be-twenty-years-later-i-wrote-a-tetris-again&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.levit.be/twenty-years-later-i-wrote-a-tetris-again/&#34;&gt; Twenty years later I wrote a Tetris&amp;hellip; again! &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere around 4am that night, after several hundred lines of Basic code, I had myself a fully working Tetris-like. It&amp;rsquo;s only a few days later that I realized I had written the same kind of program, twice, twenty years apart and in two different but somewhat similar languages. About the time it took: Surprisingly with improved tools and an extra 20 years experience, it took me about the same time this time around as it did 20 years ago. Have they been lying to us all these years telling us that with improved tools we are able to write code faster? From this experience I would say &amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;rdquo;. About the size of the code: the code I wrote this time is roughly one third of the size of my original code which probably means it has less bugs and is more maintainable. In shorter terms, the code I ended-up with in 2016 is way more re-usable than the one from 1996. Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve been rambling on and on about 2 different Tetris games coded 20 years apart, you probably want to see the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-in-one-api-documentation-browser-with-offline-mode-and-instant-search-http-devdocs-io&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://devdocs.io&#34;&gt; All-in-one API documentation browser with offline mode and instant search &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-official-oracle-will-appeal-its-fair-use-loss-against-google-http-arstechnica-com-tech-policy-2016-10-its-official-oracle-will-appeal-its-fair-use-loss-against-google&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2016/10/its-official-oracle-will-appeal-its-fair-use-loss-against-google/&#34;&gt; It’s official: Oracle will appeal its “fair use” loss against Google &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The massive Oracle v. Google litigation has entered a new phase, as Oracle filed papers yesterday saying it will appeal its loss on &amp;ldquo;Fair use&amp;rdquo; grounds to the US Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit. For a brief recap of the case: after Oracle purchased Sun Microsystems and acquired the rights to Java, it sued Google in 2010, saying that Google infringed copyrights and patents related to Java. Oracle initially lost but had part of its case revived on appeal. The sole issue in the second trial was whether Google infringed the APIs in Java, which the appeals court held are copyrighted. Oracle&amp;rsquo;s appeal is no surprise, but it will be a long shot. Oracle&amp;rsquo;s post-trial motions, which the district court judge rejected, indicate the tack it might try to take on appeal. Unless Oracle pulls off a stunning move on appeal, its massive legal expenditures in this case will be for naught.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;go-now-has-sub-millisecond-gc-pause-times-https-groups-google-com-forum-m-topic-golang-dev-ab1sfeozg-8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/m/#!topic/golang-dev/Ab1sFeoZg_8&#34;&gt; Go now has sub-millisecond GC pause times &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-more-distracting-than-a-noisy-co-worker-turns-out-not-much-http-www-npr-org-2016-10-26-498850659-what-s-more-distracting-than-a-noisy-coworker-not-much&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/2016/10/26/498850659/what-s-more-distracting-than-a-noisy-coworker-not-much&#34;&gt; What&amp;rsquo;s More Distracting Than A Noisy Co-Worker? Turns Out, Not Much &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to workplace design expert Alan Hedge at Cornell, 74 percent of workers say they face &amp;ldquo;Many&amp;rdquo; instances of disturbances and distractions from noise. The University of California&amp;rsquo;s Center for the Built Environment has a study showing workers are happier when they are in enclosed offices and less likely to take sick days. It&amp;rsquo;s only months later, when he was moved to a new desk in an office reshuffling, that he realized just how much more work he accomplished without constant interruption. In a previous job, Dooley shared an office with a man who liked to eat frozen carrots and had the hacking cough of someone with chronic bronchitis. While employers worry about contagion and lost productivity of someone bringing an illness to work, they also have a legal obligation to accommodate employees who have an illness or a disability. Four years ago, the Social Security Administration reprimanded a worker for his &amp;ldquo;Excessive flatulence.&amp;rdquo; After numerous complaints and warnings, the agency charged him with &amp;ldquo;Conduct unbecoming a federal employee.&amp;rdquo; The employee claimed he had lactose intolerance, and after his union intervened, the reprimand was rescinded. The trend toward open offices and hard office furniture makes noise distraction worse, so adding carpet, drapes and upholstery can help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lesson-learned-from-running-a-local-meetup-http-andygrunwald-com-blog-lesson-learned-from-running-a-local-meetup&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://andygrunwald.com/blog/lesson-learned-from-running-a-local-meetup/&#34;&gt; Lesson learned from running a local meetup &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good / usable location is important for the meetup and the location depends on the meetup content. If you a running your meetup in a small conference room with ~15 people you often don&amp;rsquo;t need this. Try to motivate people from your community and local meetup to get on stage for the first time. If your meetup is well known, sometimes speaker will contact you, because they knew that it is possible to test bigger conference talks at local usergroups and improve them later. Name of the meetup WiFi access Office / location rules Where are the toilets Announcements of other appointments like other meetups in the area conferences / hackathons near by your next meetup Speaker and topic of today If you offer a socialising after the talk or if the meetup ends directly. If you run a meetup or visit meetups on a regular basis, feel free to share your lessons learned in the comments. Found a bug in this article? Feel free to create a pull request at Lessons learned from running a local meetup at github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to become an enterprise developer and other personal rants ?</title>
      <link>http://iszlai.github.io/post/how-to-become-an-enterprise-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 13:27:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://iszlai.github.io/post/how-to-become-an-enterprise-developer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First of all this is a personal post with lot of questions, insecurities and rants. Really any answer reply&amp;rsquo;s, tweet, PM, email anything would be useful and help me at this point. But first let me give a bit of a background of how I got to this stage in the first place.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve studied programming since highscool all throughout University I had a CS major so I have/had the basics covered. While in Uni they hired me as a &amp;ldquo;Test automation engineer&amp;rdquo; but what I ended up doing was mostly manual testing with very little coding (or thinking by the way) &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://iszlai.github.io/images/qa.gif&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;QA&#34; /&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
with continuous promises of getting in the development side. Which never came, so one day almost after a year of getting fed up I decided I would move on.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved to another city get a job at a respected international financial firm and went trough their graduate program. It was wonderful they really tried their best to teach us about all the low level intricate details of *nix systems and C/C++ differences and idioms and a short introductory to function side with a bit of Scala.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the program we where pre-placed in teams ,and although I always had more affinity for backend related task and technology someone decided I will do Flash/Flex development on a huge system but with the promise I&amp;rsquo;ll get to work the backend as well.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a year since and almost all I did was UI development and it really doesn&amp;rsquo;t suit me, while I rarely had the chance but everytime I could do any minor change on the Java backend I was really happy. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong it was hard with virtually any experience with a 500k lines of code base.
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://iszlai.github.io/images/feel.gif&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Feel&#34; /&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
 It was/is really hard to find way trough it. Since it is a 6 years+ old project most of the original team has moved on and any bit of documentation outdated.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did my best to learn the theory and I can say fairly confident that I know how dependency injection works, I can use Spring and can modify the components based on the code that&amp;rsquo;s already present. I know how ORMs work and even wrote a toy one for myself at home just to get a deeper understanding. I read a lot about and in theory know and understand design patterns.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my problem is that certain thing just don&amp;rsquo;t click in my mind. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly the why&amp;rsquo;s. Why are there factories everywhere, why are there builders upon builder, things like AbstractProxyBeanFactory and the like make me hold my head and scream. Why are things like VisitorAdapter (just like this ) defined. Why and who thought SOAP was a good a idea to communicate with integration partners.
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://iszlai.github.io/images/legacy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Knowledge&#34; /&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
 I find my self lost with no guidance at all, I rarely get to write code in the backend and feel that my home pet projects are not enough to learn certain things like this.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my questions are as follows:
How to learn ,to understand and to get better at this type of code? I thought about open source but find it really heard to contribute to anything meaningfull. It&amp;rsquo;s either also huge without anybody to ask, or I&amp;rsquo;ve read here or there that they are impatient with new people, or all they have time for is a readily made pull request.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My final question is on a related ,topic is should a try to master Java more or focus on more new and trendy stuff ?Thing is I really feel like this &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://iszlai.github.io/images/aprox.gif&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Knowledge&#34; /&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
,and feel like I really should try to focus on one thing just don&amp;rsquo;t really know on what.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eclipse Survival Guide</title>
      <link>http://iszlai.github.io/post/eclipse-survival-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 13:27:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://iszlai.github.io/post/eclipse-survival-guide/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;After starting with Java, Scala, C++ or any other language you probably start using an ide, well there are many out there for everyones personal preferences I&amp;rsquo;ll mainly focus on Eclipse.It&amp;rsquo;s an Open Source IDE, mostly provided in Java, but it supports other the development languages by being extended with plug-ins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;turn-on-line-numbers&#34;&gt;Turn on line numbers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seems trivial but it&amp;rsquo;s really useful when you work on a team or want to find something at a specific line. All you have to do is right click the gutter and choose &lt;strong&gt;Show line numbers&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a simple tip but often useful and you only have to do it once.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://iszlai.github.io/images/lineNum.gif&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Show line numbers&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;go-to-line&#34;&gt;Go to line&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly you see a line number inside a log regarding an Exception all you do is fire up go to line using &lt;strong&gt;Ctrl+L&lt;/strong&gt; type the line number and hit enter.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://iszlai.github.io/images/gotoLine.gif&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Go to line&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;settings-search&#34;&gt;Settings search&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eclipse is a huge platform and is continually growing it&amp;rsquo;s really hard to find keep in mind where you can find the appropriate settings. Luckily theres a search for the settings.
Let&amp;rsquo;s try to find the JRE settings as it&amp;rsquo;s commonly needed. So all you do is go to settings which can be found at &lt;strong&gt;Window&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Preferences&lt;/strong&gt; and type what you are searching for like &lt;strong&gt;JRE&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://iszlai.github.io/images/settingsSearch.gif&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Settings&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;type-hierarchy&#34;&gt;Type hierarchy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever wanted to know the whole supertype tree of a class of a class or to find the abstract type ? Using supertype hierarchy with &lt;strong&gt;Ctrl&lt;/strong&gt;+&lt;strong&gt;T&lt;/strong&gt; .
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://iszlai.github.io/images/supertype.gif&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Supertype&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;comment-out-a-block&#34;&gt;Comment out a block&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When in a hurry you want to check something out, and don&amp;rsquo;t want the change to last, you could just easily comment out a block using &lt;strong&gt;Ctrl&lt;/strong&gt;+&lt;strong&gt;Shift&lt;/strong&gt;+&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;.
After you&amp;rsquo;re done repeat the same to undo it. This is also available for majority of languages so don&amp;rsquo;t have to type &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;!-- --&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; in xml ever again.Side note never leave commented out code blocks in code, it&amp;rsquo;s messy and it makes the code harder to read, and there really is no reason to keep it anyway thats what the source control is for.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://iszlai.github.io/images/comment.gif&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Comment&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;extract-method&#34;&gt;Extract method&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While refactoring you find a huge chunk of code that really should be a a method. So you could just create a method copy the chunk out, figure out the parameters and make it work. Or you could the IDE do most the work and just check the result. All you do is &lt;strong&gt;Alt&lt;/strong&gt;+&lt;strong&gt;Shift&lt;/strong&gt;+&lt;strong&gt;M&lt;/strong&gt; and give a method name.As you can see eclipse really does a pretty fine job on it&amp;rsquo;s own and saves you a lot of time.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://iszlai.github.io/images/extract.gif&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Extract method&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;delete-a-line&#34;&gt;Delete a line&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t you just have it when there are empty lines in the wrong place ? Using &lt;strong&gt;Ctrl&lt;/strong&gt;+&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt; you delete the current line, it&amp;rsquo;s really like Vim&amp;rsquo;s DD command if that ain&amp;rsquo;t a reason to love it, i don&amp;rsquo;t know what is.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://iszlai.github.io/images/delete.gif&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Delete a line&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;find-references&#34;&gt;Find references&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to change something but you aren&amp;rsquo;t sure if it&amp;rsquo;s used by anything else or what else might be affected. In this case all you do is &lt;strong&gt;Right-click&lt;/strong&gt;+&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;+&lt;strong&gt;scope&lt;/strong&gt; (like workspace, project, etc)
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://iszlai.github.io/images/refferences.gif&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;References&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;generate-code&#34;&gt;Generate code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often you find yourself writing a bit boiler plate code like getters/setters, toString, simple constructors.All this can be done by eclipse for you in a pretty find grained matter. All you do is &lt;strong&gt;Right-click&lt;/strong&gt;+&lt;strong&gt;Source&lt;/strong&gt;+what code you want to generate.
You can choose things like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getters and Setters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delegate methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hashCode() and equals()&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;toString()&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constructors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This bit can make you really productive but also please be careful don&amp;rsquo;t let the IDE make design decisions for you if you don&amp;rsquo;t need it don&amp;rsquo;t add it it will be just a cluttered code.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://iszlai.github.io/images/generate.gif&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Generate&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-resource&#34;&gt;Open resource&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are working on a project with hundreds of files packages and a complex structure if you have sort of memory about what a file is called you can try opening it with open resources .To use it all you need is &lt;strong&gt;Ctrl&lt;/strong&gt;+&lt;strong&gt;Shift&lt;/strong&gt;+&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt; ,and name in which you can also use &lt;code&gt;?&lt;/code&gt; for any character match and &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; any string match
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://iszlai.github.io/images/openRes.gif&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Open resources&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-declaration-implementation&#34;&gt;Open declaration/implementation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you see a method or an object and you would like to know where it&amp;rsquo;s declared or where it&amp;rsquo;s implemented you just hold down &lt;strong&gt;Ctrl&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;click&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://iszlai.github.io/images/openDec.gif&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Open declaration/implementation&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;search&#34;&gt;Search&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The search in eclipse is really powerful and has many functionalities to cover all of them it would take quite a lot.The two main things I would like to point out are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search and replace in file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The typical file search and replace theres not a lot to talk about it. All you do is &lt;strong&gt;Ctrl&lt;/strong&gt;+&lt;strong&gt;F&lt;/strong&gt; and then the usual functionality you would expect is there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search workspace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A more powerful search with filtering capabilities on file type and search scope.I couldn&amp;rsquo;t live without it on a windows box it&amp;rsquo;s almost as good as &lt;code&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt; .To use it all you need is &lt;strong&gt;Ctrl&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;H&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://iszlai.github.io/images/searchH.gif&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Search&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://iszlai.github.io/post/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 20:53:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://iszlai.github.io/post/about-me/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;My primary interest is to learn how to design software systems, so as to maximize the productivity of development teams. In doing this I try to look at current technological landscape and investigate software with good design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grew up in Marosvasarhely, Romania when to Babeş-Bolyai University
Faculty of Mathematics and Computer Science. My dissertation was about JavaScript based grid computing. During the time I was an intern at a mobile development company where I did Android development and have worked at an outsource firm where I did test automation. After graduating a moved to Budapest, Hungary where I started to work at a leading financial institution, trough which I had a chance to learn at the international offices in New York and London.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>